<PROJECT_SET>
<PROJECT accession="PRJDB14547" alias="PRJDB14547" center_name="Northeast Forestry University" broker_name="DDBJ">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJDB14547</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="Northeast Forestry University">PRJDB14547</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Aplectana chamaeleonis</NAME>
  <TITLE>The first genome assembly of the amphibian nematode parasite (Aplectana chamaeleonis)</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>Cosmocercoid nematodes are common parasites in the digestive tract of amphibians. Genomic resources are important for understanding the evolution of a species and the molecular mechanisms of parasite adaptation. So far, no genome resource of Cosmocercoid has been reported. In 2020, a massive infection of the parasite was found in the small intestine of an amphibian toad, causing a severe intestinal blockage. We identified this parasite as A. chamaeleonis morphologically. Here, we report for the first time a highly contiguous A. chamaeleonis genome with a genome size of 1.1Gb. The repeat content in the Ascaris genome is 72.45%, and the total length is more than 742Mb. This study is of great significance for understanding the evolution of Cosmocercoid, and also provides a molecular basis for Cosmocercoid infection and control.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>2696335</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Aplectana chamaeleonis</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA893801"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJDB14547&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJDB14547&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>890066</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2022-10-15</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJEB10852" alias="ena-STUDY-Division of Nematology, IARI, New Delhi-15-09-2015-10:23:41:683-360" center_name="Division of Nematology, IARI, New Delhi">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJEB10852</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="Division of Nematology, IARI, New Delhi">ena-STUDY-Division of Nematology, IARI, New Delhi-15-09-2015-10:23:41:683-360</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Heterorhabditis indica IJ transcriptome</NAME>
  <TITLE>A transcriptomic insight into the infective juvenile stage of the insect parasitic nematode, Heterorhabditis indica</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>Nematodes are the most numerous animals in soil. Insect parasitic nematodes of the genus Heterorhabditis are capable of selectively seeking, infecting and killing their insect hosts in soil. The infective juvenile (IJ) stage of the Heterorhabditis nematodes is analogous to Caenorhabditis elegans dauer juvenile stage, which remains in ‘arrested development’ till it finds and infects a new insect-host in soil. H. indica is the most prevalent species of Heterorhabditis in India. To understand the genes and molecular processes that govern the the biology of the IJ stage of H. indica, and to create the foundation for genetic exploration of H. indica, we sequenced the transcriptome of H. indica IJs.  The de-novo sequence assembly using velvet - oases pipeline resulted in 18,710 contigs with N50 of 909 bp. However, after using cd-hit-est and filtering out &lt;300bp transcripts, 13,592 unique transcripts were identified, and N50 increased to 1371. Orthologs of the genes expressing in IJ stage of the H indica  were identified by comparing these 13,592 protein sequences with complete genomes of other closely related rhabditid nematodes through reciprocal blast approach which revealed  3364 orthologs with C. elegans, 3103 with C. briggsae, 2164 with Pristionchus pacificus, 346 with H. bacteriophora, and 3171 orthologs with C. remanei. Further, H. indica transcriptome was compared with the available plant, animal and human parasitic nematode genome sequences. We found 9906 and 8892 protein matches with Meloidogyne hapla and M. incognita respectively, 9685 with Ascaris suum, 9051 with Brugia malayi, 8188 with Strongyloides ratti and 7588 with Trichinella spiralis.  Similar to C. elegans, all the four dauer formation pathways - cGMP - PKG signaling pathway, Insulin signaling pathway, Dafachronic acid pathway and TGF-β are were conserved and active in the IJ stage H. indica. Several important signaling pathways were found active in the IJs indicating that in-spite of being a developmentally arrested stage, IJs are a hot bed of signalling and are actively interacting with their environment. Similarly, glycolysis and fatty acid degradation pathways were highly active in IJs indicating breakdown of food reserves. Twenty four orthologs of C. elegans RNAi pathway effector genes were found in H. indica IJ transcriptome, including nrde-3 which has been identified for the first time in any of the parasitic worms.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT>
      <LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>BN2691</LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>
    </SEQUENCING_PROJECT>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMISSION</DB>
        <ID>ERA484809</ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJEB10852&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJEB10852&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2015-09-15</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2016-05-20</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJEB1781" alias="Human_infections_with_the_whipworm__Trichuris_trichiura__are_not_associated_with_alterations_in_the_faecal_microbiota_-sc-2013-04-11T16:02:20Z-2595" center_name="Wellcome Sanger Institute">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJEB1781</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="Wellcome Sanger Institute">Human_infections_with_the_whipworm__Trichuris_trichiura__are_not_associated_with_alterations_in_the_faecal_microbiota_-sc-2013-04-11T16:02:20Z-2595</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Human_infections_with_the_whipworm__Trichuris_trichiura__are_not_associated_with_alterations_in_the_faecal_microbiota_</NAME>
  <TITLE>Human_infections_with_the_whipworm__Trichuris_trichiura__are_not_associated_with_alterations_in_the_faecal_microbiota_</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>Materials and Methods: We carried out the study in two rural communities 
in Esmeraldas Province, Ecuador. School-age children were screened for 
the presence of STH infections and allocated to one of 3 groups: 
uninfected, T. trichiura only, and mixed infections with T. trichiura 
and Ascaris lumbricoides. A sample of uninfected children and those with 
T. trichiura infections only were treated with albendazole (800 mg/day 
for 3 days) and ivermectin (single dose of 200 ug/kg), and stool samples 
were collected 3 weeks post-treatment. Bacterial DNA was extracted using 
the FastDNA Spin kit for soil, and bacterial community profiles were 
studied by 454 pyrosequencing of 16S rRNA genes. This generated 999,796 
sequences, which were processed and analysed using mothur.

Results: Microbiota analyses were done using stool samples from 97 
children aged 8-14 years of whom 30 were not infected, 17 were infected 
with T. trichiura alone, and 50 had mixed infections with both T. 
trichiura and A. lumbricoides. Post-treatment samples were analyzed for 
14 of the 17 children initially infected with T. trichiura alone and 21 
of 30 uninfected children. Treatment resulted in 100% cure of STH 
infections. Comparisons of the microbiota at different taxonomic levels 
showed no statistically significant differences in composition between 
uninfected children and those with T. trichiura infections. A surprising 
finding was a decreased proportional abundance of a few bacterial genera 
from the clostridia class of Firmicutes, in tandem with a reduced 
overall bacterial diversity, among children with mixed infections 
compared to either uninfected children or those with T. trichiura 
infections only, indicating a specific effect of A. lumbricoides 
infection on intestinal microbiota.  Anthelmintic treatment of children 
with T. trichiura did not appear to alter composition of faecal microbiota.

Discussion: This is the first molecular study to analyse the effect of 
whipworm infection on the human intestinal microbiota. Our data indicate 
that T. trichiura infections alone have no effect on the faecal 
microbiota of children living in endemic communities, but that A. 
lumbricoides colonisation might be associated with a disturbed 
microbiota. Our results also catalogue the microbiota that is present in 
rural Ecuadorians, and indicate that there are differences between this 
cohort and individuals from more urban, industrialised societies.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMISSION</DB>
        <ID>ERA206857</ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJEB1781&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJEB1781&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2013-04-17</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2016-05-20</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJEB19398" alias="ena-STUDY-UNIVERSITY OF COPENH-10-02-2017-15:09:02:778-130" center_name="University of Copenh">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJEB19398</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="University of Copenh">ena-STUDY-UNIVERSITY OF COPENH-10-02-2017-15:09:02:778-130</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Pigs infected with Ascaris suum</NAME>
  <TITLE>Dietary polyphenols modulate mucosal immune responses and gut microbiota composition in pigs infected with Ascaris suum</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>Proanthocyanidins (PAC) are a class of polyphenols found in many plants. Diets rich in PAC are thought to have beneficial effects on gut health, such as regulation of parasite burdens and modulation of mucosal immune and inflammatory responses. Here, we examined the interactions between a PAC-rich diet supplement and Ascaris suum infection in pigs. Pigs were fed either a basal diet or the same diet supplemented with PAC-rich grape pomace (GP), and then half of the animals were inoculated with A. suum. Parasite establishment was not altered by GP-supplementation. However, the bioactive diet significantly increased numbers of eosinophils induced by A. suum infection in the duodenum, jejunum and ileum, and modulated gene expression in the jejunal mucosa of infected pigs. GP-supplementation increased the concentration of propionic acid in the colon, whilst both GP-supplementation and A. suum infection decreased concentrations of isobutyric and isovaleric acid. The effects of both GP-supplementation and A. suum on the composition of the host prokaryotic gut microbiota were qualitatively similar, however A. suum had a stronger influence than diet. Our results demonstrate that a PAC-rich diet supplement in pigs significantly modulates the host response to helminth infection. Our results indicate an important influence of diet on immune function during parasite infection, which may potentially be exploited to improve gut health.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMISSION</DB>
        <ID>ERA812712</ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJEB19398&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJEB19398&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2017-04-09</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2017-02-10</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJEB2435" alias="The_genome_sequence_of_the_intestinal_roundworm_Ascaris_suum-sc-2011-02-25" center_name="Wellcome Sanger Institute">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJEB2435</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SECONDARY_ID>ERP000532</SECONDARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="Wellcome Sanger Institute">The_genome_sequence_of_the_intestinal_roundworm_Ascaris_suum-sc-2011-02-25</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>The_genome_sequence_of_the_intestinal_roundworm_Ascaris_suum</NAME>
  <TITLE>The_genome_sequence_of_the_intestinal_roundworm_Ascaris_suum</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>Ascaris spp are the largest intestinal worms and responsible for ascariasis, the commonest helminth infection of humans worldwide. Adult Ascaris live in the small intestine, where each female can produce hundreds of thousands of eggs each day. Eggs are passed into the environment where, over about 10 days, they develop into larvae. This takes place in the soil, thus Ascaris (along with hookworms and whipworms) are classified as soil-transmitted helminths.
Human infections are common in sub-tropical and tropical areas with poor sanitation and are predominantly due to the species A. lumbricoides. A closely related species A. suum typically infects pigs.  The aim of this project is to sequence and analyse the nuclear genome of Ascaris suum with the goal of producing a reference quality genome sequence. The genome will be used for comparative genomics for related worms and as a reference for gene finding using RNA-seq. . This data is part of a pre-publication release. For information on the proper use of pre-publication data shared by the Wellcome Trust Sanger Institute (including details of any publication moratoria), please see http://www.sanger.ac.uk/datasharing/</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMISSION</DB>
        <ID>ERA021710</ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJEB2435&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJEB2435&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2011-07-07</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2016-05-20</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJEB32283" alias="Testing_approaches_to_sequence_larval_stages_of_nematodes-sc-5249" center_name="Wellcome Sanger Institute">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJEB32283</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="Wellcome Sanger Institute">Testing_approaches_to_sequence_larval_stages_of_nematodes-sc-5249</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Testing_approaches_to_sequence_larval_stages_of_nematodes</NAME>
  <TITLE>Testing_approaches_to_sequence_larval_stages_of_nematodes</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>For many parasitic nematode species, adults inhabit the GI tract and eggs are shed in faeces and subsequently develop through larval stages in the faeces or soil before infective larvae are either ingested or penetrate the skin of hosts to complete the lifecycle. Worms with this broad type of lifecycle include important human pathogens like hookworms, Ascaris, Strongyloides species, and Trichuris as well as many key veterinary parasites. For most of these, accessing adult parasites is difficult, so genetic surveillance of their populations depend on egg material, or larval stages that can, in general, easily be obtained from eggs by brief incubation of stool samples. This project will investigate methods for sequencing eggs and early larval stages.
This data is part of a pre-publication release. For information on the proper use of pre-publication data shared by the Wellcome Trust Sanger Institute (including details of any publication moratoria), please see http://www.sanger.ac.uk/datasharing/</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMISSION</DB>
        <ID>ERA1853117</ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJEB32283&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJEB32283&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2019-04-24</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2019-04-24</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJEB35530" alias="ena-STUDY-UNIVERSITY OF SASSARI-25-11-2019-09:55:16:474-775" center_name="UNIVERSITY OF SASSARI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJEB35530</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="UNIVERSITY OF SASSARI">ena-STUDY-UNIVERSITY OF SASSARI-25-11-2019-09:55:16:474-775</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Palazzo_Ducale_SS</NAME>
  <TITLE>Latrine inside an old palace (18th century) (Sassari - Italy)</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>This study evidenced the presence of parasites in a cesspit of an aristocratic palace of 19th century in Sardinia (Italy) by the use of classical paleoparasitological techniques coupled with next-generation sequencing. Parasite eggs identified by microscopy included helminth genera pathogenic for humans and animals: the whipworm Trichuris sp., the roundworm Ascaris sp., the flatworm Dicrocoelium sp. and the fish tapeworm Diphyllobothrium sp. In addition, 18S rRNA metabarcoding and metagenomic sequencing analysis allowed the first description in Sardinia of aDNA of the human specific T. trichiura and A. lumbricoides species. Their presence is important for understanding the health conditions, hygiene habits, agricultural practices and the diet of the local inhabitants in the period under study.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMISSION</DB>
        <ID>ERA2299375</ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJEB35530&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJEB35530&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2019-11-26</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2019-11-25</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJEB4950" alias="ALUE:" center_name="WELLCOME SANGER INSTITUTE">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJEB4950</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="WELLCOME SANGER INSTITUTE">ALUE:</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Ascaris lumbricoides Genome sequencing</NAME>
  <TITLE>Genomic assembly of nematode Ascaris lumbricoides, as part of the 50 Helminth Genomes Initiative; sequencing of the parasitic worms that have the greatest impact on human, agricultural and veterinary disease and cause significant global health issues particularly in the developing world, or those used as model organisms.</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>Despite their importance globally, both medically and economically, parasitic helminth (worm) research has remained relatively untouched by genomics. Worm infections account for morbidity equivalent to more than 100 million disability-adjusted life years from more than one billion infections globally. The 50 Helminth Genomes Initiative is collaborative project that aims to survey the genomes of nematodes and platyhelminths that are either of medical or veterinary importance, or as used as models for those. It will include all the neglected metazoan parasites. Preliminary illumina sequencing from these helminth species will be used to produce draft genomic assemblies which will create a unique genomic resource. Draft assemblies of the genomes will underpin research and progress into these neglected diseases. Gene and protein predictions will provide a resource that can be mined by researchers for diagnostic markers, new drug targets or vaccines. Comparing the genomes will yield evolutionary insights and will enable more to be learnt about the genomic basis for the huge differences in the biology of these parasites and the diseases they cause.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT>
      <LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>ALUE</LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>
    </SEQUENCING_PROJECT>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>6252</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Ascaris lumbricoides</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
      <COMMON_NAME>common roundworm</COMMON_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA77195"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMISSION</DB>
        <ID>ERA266424</ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJEB4950&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJEB4950&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2014-09-19</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2021-01-08</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJEB76471" alias="E-MTAB-14168" broker_name="ArrayExpress" center_name="European Bioinformatics Institute">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJEB76471</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="European Bioinformatics Institute">E-MTAB-14168</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>MiRNA profiles of host extracellular vesicles are modulated by Ascaris suum infection but parasite extracellular vesicle miRNAs are undetectable systemically using in-depth miRNA sequencing</NAME>
  <TITLE>MiRNA profiles of host extracellular vesicles are modulated by Ascaris suum infection but parasite extracellular vesicle miRNAs are undetectable systemically using in-depth miRNA sequencing</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>RNAseq analysis of extracellular vesicles isolated from control pigs and pigs infected with Ascaris suum</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <URL_LINK>
        <URL>https://www.ebi.ac.uk/biostudies/arrayexpress/studies/E-MTAB-14168</URL>
        <LABEL>E-MTAB-14168 in ArrayExpress</LABEL>
      </URL_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMISSION</DB>
        <ID>ERA30589488</ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJEB76471&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJEB76471&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2024-08-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2024-08-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA1000709" alias="PRJNA1000709" center_name="Universiti Teknologi MARA" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA1000709</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="Universiti Teknologi MARA">PRJNA1000709</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <TITLE>Gut microbiome of Ascaris lumbricoides and its human host</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>Ascaris lumbricoides harbors a distinct gut microbiota from its human host</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA1000709&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA1000709&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>1000709</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2023-08-02</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2023-08-02</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA1054112" alias="PRJNA1054112" center_name="BEA core facility, Department of Biosciences and Nutrition, Karolinska Institute" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA1054112</PRIMARY_ID>
    <EXTERNAL_ID namespace="GEO">GSE250463</EXTERNAL_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="BEA core facility, Department of Biosciences and Nutrition, Karolinska Institute">PRJNA1054112</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Cystatin from the helminth Ascaris lumbricoides (Al-CPI) upregulates mevalonate and cholesterol biosynthesis pathways and immunomodulatory genes in human monocyte-derived dendritic cells (moDC)</NAME>
  <TITLE>Cystatin from the helminth Ascaris lumbricoides (Al-CPI) upregulates mevalonate and cholesterol biosynthesis pathways and immunomodulatory genes in human monocyte-derived dendritic cells (moDC)</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>Background: Ascaris lumbricoides cystatin (Al-CPI) prevents development of allergic airway inflammation and colitis in mice models. It has been suggested that helminth derived cystatins inhibit cathepsins in dendritic cells (DC), but their immunomodulatory mechanisms are unclear. We aimed to analyze the transcriptional profile of human monocyte derived DC (moDC) upon stimulation with Al-CPI to elucidate target genes and pathways of parasite immunomodulation. Methods: moDC were generated from peripheral blood monocytes from six healthy human donors of Denmark, stimulated with 1 μM of Al-CPI and cultured for 5 hours at 37°C. RNA was sequenced using TrueSeq RNA libraries and the NextSeq 550 v2.5 (75 cycles) sequencing kit (Illumina, Inc). After QC, reads were aligned to the human GRCh38 genome using STAR. Differential expression was calculated by DESEq2 and expressed in fold changes (FC). Cell surface markers and cytokine production by moDC were evaluated by flow cytometry. Results: Compared to unstimulated cells, Al‐CPI stimulated moDC showed differential expression of 444 transcripts (|FC| ≥1.3). The top significant differences were in kruppel like factor 10 (KLF10, FC 3.3, PBH = 3 x 10-136 ), palladin (FC 2, PBH = 3 x 10-41 ) and the low-density lipoprotein receptor (LDLR, FC 2.6, PBH = 5 x 10-41 ). Upregulated genes were enriched in regulation of cholesterol biosynthesis by sterol regulatory element-binding proteins (SREBP) signaling pathways. Several genes in the cholesterol biosynthetic pathway showed significantly increased expression upon Al-CPI stimulation, even in the presence of LPS. Regarding the pathway of negative regulation of immune response, we found significant decrease in cell surface expression of CD86, HLA-DR and PD-L1 upon stimulation with 1 μM Al-CPI. Conclusion: Al-CPI modifies the transcriptome of moDC, increasing several transcripts encoding enzymes involved in cholesterol biosynthesis and SREBP signaling. Moreover, Al-CPI target several transcripts in the TNF-alpha signaling pathway influencing cytokine release by moDC. Several SMADs, members of the TGF-beta and the IL-10 families, including KLF10 were also This is a provisional file, not the final typeset article modified by Al-CPI stimulation. The regulation of the mevalonate pathway and cholesterol biosynthesis suggests new mechanisms involved in DC responses to helminth immunomodulatory molecules. Overall design: To identify immunomodulatory mechanisms of Ascaris lumbricoides cystatin, we analyzed differentially expressed genes in human monocyte-derived dendritic cells stimulated with Al-CPI 0.1 uM, Al-CPI 1 uM, LPS, LPS + Al-CPI 0.1 uM, Al-CPI + LPS 1 uM, or LPS + ABF (n = 6 biological replicates per condition). moDCs grown in culture medium only was used as negative control.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>9606</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Homo sapiens</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA9558"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>PUBMED</DB>
        <ID>38481989</ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA1054112&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA1054112&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>1054112</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2024-01-17</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA1067589" alias="PRJNA1067589" center_name="The University of Tennessee, Knoxville" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA1067589</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="The University of Tennessee, Knoxville">PRJNA1067589</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Parascaris univalens isolate:Wild isolate</NAME>
  <TITLE>Parascaris univalens isolate:Wild isolate Genome sequencing and assembly</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>A growing list of metazoans undergo programmed DNA elimination (PDE), where a significant amount of DNA is selectively lost from the genome during development. In some nematodes, PDE leads to the removal of the ends of all germline chromosomes. In several species, PDE also eliminates sequences in the interior of the chromosomes, leading to an increased number of somatic chromosomes. The biological significance of these karyotype changes associated with PDE and the origin and evolution of nematode PDE remain largely unknown. Here, we assembled the single pair of germline chromosomes of the horse parasite Parascaris univalens and compared the karyotypes, gene organization within the chromosomes, and PDE features among ascarids. We show that Parascaris converts an XX/XY sex-determination system in the germline into an XX/XO system in the somatic cells. Comparisons of Ascaris, Parascaris, and Baylisascaris chromosomes suggest that PDE existed in the ancestor of these parasites, and their current distinct germline karyotypes were derived from fusion events of the same ancestral smaller chromosomes. PDE resolves these fused germline chromosomes and restores their pre-fusion karyotypes, leading to alterations in genome architecture and gene expression in the somatic cells. Cytological and genomic analyses further reveal the dynamic organization of the Parascaris germline chromosome during meiosis and a potential function for the satellite DNA and the heterochromatin arms. Overall, our results show that chromosome fusion and PDE have been harnessed in these ascarids to shape their karyotypes that could modulate the organization and functions of the genomes.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT>
      <LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>VYM95</LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>
    </SEQUENCING_PROJECT>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>6257</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Parascaris univalens</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA386832"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA1067589&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA1067589&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>1067589</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2024-02-20</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA1071986" alias="PRJNA1071986" center_name="The University of Tennessee" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA1071986</PRIMARY_ID>
    <EXTERNAL_ID namespace="GEO">GSE254811</EXTERNAL_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="The University of Tennessee">PRJNA1071986</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Chromosome fusion and programmed DNA elimination shape karyotypes of parasitic nematodes [Hi-C]</NAME>
  <TITLE>Chromosome fusion and programmed DNA elimination shape karyotypes of parasitic nematodes [Hi-C]</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>A growing list of metazoans undergo programmed DNA elimination (PDE), where a significant amount of DNA is selectively lost from the genome during development. In some nematodes, PDE leads to the removal of the ends of all germline chromosomes. In several species, PDE also eliminates sequences in the interior of the chromosomes, leading to an increased number of somatic chromosomes. The biological significance of these karyotype changes associated with PDE and the origin and evolution of nematode PDE remain largely unknown. Here, we assembled the single pair of germline chromosomes of the horse parasite Parascaris univalens and compared the karyotypes, gene organization within the chromosomes, and PDE features among ascarids. We show that Parascaris converts an XX/XY sex-determination system in the germline into an XX/XO system in the somatic cells. Comparisons of Ascaris, Parascaris, and Baylisascaris chromosomes suggest that PDE existed in the ancestor of these parasites, and their current distinct germline karyotypes were derived from fusion events of the same ancestral smaller chromosomes. PDE resolves these fused germline chromosomes and restores their pre-fusion karyotypes, leading to alterations in genome architecture and gene expression in the somatic cells. Cytological and genomic analyses further reveal the dynamic organization of the Parascaris germline chromosome during meiosis and a potential function for the satellite DNA and the heterochromatin arms. Overall, our results show that chromosome fusion and PDE have been harnessed in these ascarids to shape their karyotypes that could modulate the organization and functions of the genomes. Overall design: Hi-C was performed using samples from intestines and germlines of both adult male and female Parascaris univalens.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>6257</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Parascaris univalens</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA386832"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>PUBMED</DB>
        <ID>38688284</ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA1071986&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA1071986&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>1071986</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2024-04-24</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA1071997" alias="PRJNA1071997" center_name="The University of Tennessee" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA1071997</PRIMARY_ID>
    <EXTERNAL_ID namespace="GEO">GSE254814</EXTERNAL_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="The University of Tennessee">PRJNA1071997</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Chromosome fusion and programmed DNA elimination shape karyotypes of parasitic nematodes [RNA-seq]</NAME>
  <TITLE>Chromosome fusion and programmed DNA elimination shape karyotypes of parasitic nematodes [RNA-seq]</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>A growing list of metazoans undergo programmed DNA elimination (PDE), where a significant amount of DNA is selectively lost from the genome during development. In some nematodes, PDE leads to the removal of the ends of all germline chromosomes. In several species, PDE also eliminates sequences in the interior of the chromosomes, leading to an increased number of somatic chromosomes. The biological significance of these karyotype changes associated with PDE and the origin and evolution of nematode PDE remain largely unknown. Here, we assembled the single pair of germline chromosomes of the horse parasite Parascaris univalens and compared the karyotypes, gene organization within the chromosomes, and PDE features among ascarids. We show that Parascaris converts an XX/XY sex-determination system in the germline into an XX/XO system in the somatic cells. Comparisons of Ascaris, Parascaris, and Baylisascaris chromosomes suggest that PDE existed in the ancestor of these parasites, and their current distinct germline karyotypes were derived from fusion events of the same ancestral smaller chromosomes. PDE resolves these fused germline chromosomes and restores their pre-fusion karyotypes, leading to alterations in genome architecture and gene expression in the somatic cells. Cytological and genomic analyses further reveal the dynamic organization of the Parascaris germline chromosome during meiosis and a potential function for the satellite DNA and the heterochromatin arms. Overall, our results show that chromosome fusion and PDE have been harnessed in these ascarids to shape their karyotypes that could modulate the organization and functions of the genomes. Overall design: Sequencing was performed using Parascaris univalens embryos at different developmental stages and different regions of the testis.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>6257</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Parascaris univalens</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA386832"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>PUBMED</DB>
        <ID>38688284</ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA1071997&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA1071997&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>1071997</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2024-04-24</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA1072991" alias="PRJNA1072991" center_name="The University of Tennessee" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA1072991</PRIMARY_ID>
    <EXTERNAL_ID namespace="GEO">GSE254994</EXTERNAL_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="The University of Tennessee">PRJNA1072991</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Chromosome fusion and programmed DNA elimination shape karyotypes of parasitic nematodes [CUT&amp;RUN]</NAME>
  <TITLE>Chromosome fusion and programmed DNA elimination shape karyotypes of parasitic nematodes [CUT&amp;RUN]</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>A growing list of metazoans undergo programmed DNA elimination (PDE), where a significant amount of DNA is selectively lost from the genome during development. In some nematodes, PDE leads to the removal of the ends of all germline chromosomes. In several species, PDE also eliminates sequences in the interior of the chromosomes, leading to an increased number of somatic chromosomes. The biological significance of these karyotype changes associated with PDE and the origin and evolution of nematode PDE remain largely unknown. Here, we assembled the single pair of germline chromosomes of the horse parasite Parascaris univalens and compared the karyotypes, gene organization within the chromosomes, and PDE features among ascarids. We show that Parascaris converts an XX/XY sex-determination system in the germline into an XX/XO system in the somatic cells. Comparisons of Ascaris, Parascaris, and Baylisascaris chromosomes suggest that PDE existed in the ancestor of these parasites, and their current distinct germline karyotypes were derived from fusion events of the same ancestral smaller chromosomes. PDE resolves these fused germline chromosomes and restores their pre-fusion karyotypes, leading to alterations in genome architecture and gene expression in the somatic cells. Cytological and genomic analyses further reveal the dynamic organization of the Parascaris germline chromosome during meiosis and a potential function for the satellite DNA and the heterochromatin arms. Overall, our results show that chromosome fusion and PDE have been harnessed in these ascarids to shape their karyotypes that could modulate the organization and functions of the genomes. Overall design: CUT&amp;RUN sequencing data for the histone variant CENP-A and histone modifications H3K4me3 and H3K9me3. Samples are from male and female germlines of Parascaris univalens.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>6257</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Parascaris univalens</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA386832"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>PUBMED</DB>
        <ID>38688284</ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA1072991&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA1072991&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>1072991</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2024-04-24</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA1084733" alias="PRJNA1084733" center_name="420C, Biochemistry &amp; Cellular and Molecular Biology, University of Tennessee Knoxville" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA1084733</PRIMARY_ID>
    <EXTERNAL_ID namespace="GEO">GSE260958</EXTERNAL_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="420C, Biochemistry &amp; Cellular and Molecular Biology, University of Tennessee Knoxville">PRJNA1084733</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>End resection and telomere healing of DNA double-strand breaks during nematode programmed DNA elimination</NAME>
  <TITLE>End resection and telomere healing of DNA double-strand breaks during nematode programmed DNA elimination</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>Most DNA double-strand breaks (DSBs) are harmful to genome integrity. However, some forms of DSBs are essential to biological processes, such as meiotic recombination and V(D)J recombination. DSBs are also required for programmed DNA elimination (PDE) in ciliates and nematodes. In nematodes, the DSBs are healed with telomere addition. While telomere addition sites have been well-characterized, little is known regarding the DSBs that fragment nematode chromosomes. Here, we used embryos from the nematode Ascaris to study the timing of PDE breaks and examine the DSBs and their end processing. Using END-seq, we characterize the DSB ends and demonstrate that DNA breaks are introduced before mitosis, followed by extensive end resection. The resection profile is unique for each break site, and the resection generates 3’ overhangs before the addition of telomeres. Interestingly, telomere healing occurs much more frequently on retained DSB ends than on eliminated ends. This biased repair of the DSB in Ascaris is likely due to the sequestration of the eliminated DNA into micronuclei, preventing their ends from telomere healing. Additional DNA breaks occur within the eliminated DNA in both Ascaris and Parascaris, ensuring chromosomal breakage and providing a fail-safe mechanism for nematode PDE. Overall design: END-seq on Ascaris suum and Parascaris univalens early embryos undergoing programmed DNA elimination. Includes biological replicates for various stages of embryo development.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>PUBMED</DB>
        <ID>38953168</ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA1084733&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA1084733&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>1084733</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2024-03-30</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2024-07-09</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA1156568" alias="PRJNA1156568" center_name="USDA" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA1156568</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="USDA">PRJNA1156568</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <TITLE>Identification of biomarkers predictive of Ascaris infection and anthelmintics mediated worm clearance using a swine model</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>In this study, we attempt to understand how the gut microbiota shapes up host-parasite relationships using an integrated multi-omics analysis in a swine-Ascaris model. Thirty 6- to 8-month-old female pigs were randomly divided into three groups (N=10 per group). One group served as normal uninfected controls (NU); the remaining 20 pigs were inoculated per os with ~10,000 infective A. suum eggs; and the infection was allowed to progress for 35 days post-infection (dpi). At 21 dpi, one of the infected groups (IP) was treated with a single daily dose of the anthelmintic drug Panacur for three consecutive days while the other infected pigs remained untreated (IU). At necropsy, intestine pathology was scored; and serum and fecal samples were collected for untargeted metabolome analysis. The fecal microbiota was characterized using full-length 16S rRNA gene-based sequencing and the DADA2 algorithm. Fecal and serum metabolites were categorized for their origin using MetOrigin. The integrated multi-omics analysis was performed using DIABLO algorithms and NetCoMi networking tools. Our results show that A. suum worms were well developed in the infected group, which had a significantly reduced alpha diversity (Simpson, P &lt;0.005) compared to uninfected controls. The infection also altered the abundance of at least 17 bacterial species or strains, including butyrate-producing Clostridium, such as C. butyricum, altering the abundance of 51 fecal metabolites, including microbiota-derived metabolites such as glutaric acid and p-Cresol sulfate, and succinate of mixed origin. Moreover, the anthelmintic treatment was efficacious and eliminated all worms from the gut. Nevertheless, 11 pathways of both host and microbiota origin were significantly enriched in the gut of successfully treated pigs, including peptidoglycan biosynthesis, histidine metabolism (in both feces and serum), and primary bile acid biosynthesis, suggesting the infection-induced alterations may not be transient. In conclusion, the host microbiota modified swine-Ascaris interactions via three different mechanisms. First, microbiota-derived metabolites directly regulate host gene expression, which in turn affects host physiology and immune responses. Second, plasticity of the gut microbiota allows the exploitation of the niche differentiated upon infection, resulting in blossom of certain species or strains in the gut of post-treated animals. Lastly, the host microbiota is likely one of the key determinants of parasite gut microbiota, indirectly exerting its effect on parasite physiology and nutrition. Further studies aiming to understand reciprocal yet complex relations between the gut microbiota, the host, and parasites (including parasite gut microbiota) will be conducive to the design of next-generation functional anthelmintics.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA1156568&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA1156568&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>1156568</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2024-09-09</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2024-09-09</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA1193043" alias="PRJNA1193043" center_name="Post Graduate Institute of Medical Education and Research, Chandigarh" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA1193043</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="Post Graduate Institute of Medical Education and Research, Chandigarh">PRJNA1193043</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <TITLE>Whole genome sequencing of Ascaris lumbricoides</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>The goal is to is to perform whole genome sequencing, variant analysis and gene ontology&lt;/p>&lt;p>for Ascaris lumbricoides.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA1193043&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA1193043&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>1193043</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2024-12-06</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2024-12-06</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA1195031" alias="PRJNA1195031" center_name="SRUC" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA1195031</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="SRUC">PRJNA1195031</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <TITLE>Genomic Epidemiology Ascaris Lumbricoides</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>Genomic epidemiology of Ascaris lumbricoides from a single community, following multiple rounds of treatment</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA1195031&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA1195031&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>1195031</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2024-12-08</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2024-12-08</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA12863" alias="PRJNA12863" center_name="NCBI" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA12863</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="NCBI">PRJNA12863</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Ascaris suum</NAME>
  <TITLE>Large roundworm of pig</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>&lt;i>Ascaris suum&lt;/i> is an intestinal roundworm that infects pigs. Pigs become infected by ingesting &lt;i>A. suum&lt;/i> eggs which hatch in the small intestine, and then migrate to the lungs where the juvenile form is coughed up and swallowed. These juveniles mature into adults in the small intestines, mate, and produce eggs that are shed to begin the next cycle. Ingestion of the eggs of this pig roundworm can also cause a human disease, ascaris pneumonia, since the larvae migrate to the lung inducing an inflammatory response and edema.</DESCRIPTION>
  <UMBRELLA_PROJECT>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>6253</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Ascaris suum</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </UMBRELLA_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <CHILD_PROJECT accession="PRJNA12864"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <CHILD_PROJECT accession="PRJNA142039"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <CHILD_PROJECT accession="PRJNA142041"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <CHILD_PROJECT accession="PRJNA153609"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <CHILD_PROJECT accession="PRJNA167264"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <CHILD_PROJECT accession="PRJNA168099"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <CHILD_PROJECT accession="PRJNA198514"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <CHILD_PROJECT accession="PRJNA286848"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <CHILD_PROJECT accession="PRJNA308932"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <CHILD_PROJECT accession="PRJNA388699"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <CHILD_PROJECT accession="PRJNA62057"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <CHILD_PROJECT accession="PRJNA63155"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <CHILD_PROJECT accession="PRJNA69809"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <CHILD_PROJECT accession="PRJNA750737"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <CHILD_PROJECT accession="PRJNA789231"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <CHILD_PROJECT accession="PRJNA80881"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA12863&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA12863&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>12863</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>ORGANISM</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2013-06-26</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA12864" alias="PRJNA12864" center_name="NematodeNet" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA12864</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="NematodeNet">PRJNA12864</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Ascaris suum</NAME>
  <TITLE>Ascaris suum</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION><![CDATA[Parasitic Nematode Sequencing Project (<A HREF="http://www.nematode.net/index.php">NematodeNet</A>) is aiming to generate more than 300,000 ESTs from ~ 40 nematode species Sequencing will be done at at the Washington University's Genome Sequencing Center, St.Louis and Sanger Center & Edinburgh University. <A HREF="http://www.pubmedcentral.gov/articlerender.fcgi?tool=pmcentrez&rendertype=abstract&artid=308745">Read more ...</A>]]></DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>6253</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Ascaris suum</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA12863"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA286848"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA12864&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA12864&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>12864</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2013-05-31</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA136965" alias="PRJNA136965" center_name="Richard E. Davis Lab, Biochemistry and Molecular Genetics, University of Colorado Denver" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA136965</PRIMARY_ID>
    <EXTERNAL_ID namespace="GEO">GSE26957</EXTERNAL_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="Richard E. Davis Lab, Biochemistry and Molecular Genetics, University of Colorado Denver">PRJNA136965</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Deep Small RNA Sequencing from the Nematode Ascaris Reveals Conservation, Functional Diversification, and Novel Developmental Profiles</NAME>
  <TITLE>Deep Small RNA Sequencing from the Nematode Ascaris Reveals Conservation, Functional Diversification, and Novel Developmental Profiles</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>This SuperSeries is composed of the SubSeries listed below. Overall design: Refer to individual Series</DESCRIPTION>
  <UMBRELLA_PROJECT/>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <CHILD_PROJECT accession="PRJNA142039"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <CHILD_PROJECT accession="PRJNA142041"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>PUBMED</DB>
        <ID>21685128</ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA136965&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA136965&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>136965</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>UMBRELLA</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2013-05-31</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA142039" alias="PRJNA142039" center_name="Richard E. Davis Lab, Biochemistry and Molecular Genetics, University of Colorado Denver" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA142039</PRIMARY_ID>
    <EXTERNAL_ID namespace="GEO">GSE26955</EXTERNAL_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="Richard E. Davis Lab, Biochemistry and Molecular Genetics, University of Colorado Denver">PRJNA142039</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Ascaris suum</NAME>
  <TITLE>Ascaris suum Small RNA-Seq data</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>Eukaryotic cells express several classes of small RNAs that regulate gene expression and ensure genome maintenance. Endogenous siRNAs (endo-siRNAs) and Piwi-interacting RNAs (piRNAs) mainly control gene and transposon expression in the germline, while microRNAs (miRNAs) generally function in post-transcriptional gene silencing in both somatic and germline cells. To provide an evolutionary and developmental perspective on small RNA pathways in nematodes, we identified and characterized known and novel small RNA classes through gametogenesis and embryo development in the parasitic nematode Ascaris suum and compared them with known small RNAs of Caenorhabditis elegans. piRNAs, Piwi-clade Argonautes, and other proteins associated with the piRNA pathway have been lost in Ascaris. miRNAs are synthesized immediately following fertilization in utero, prior to pronuclear fusion, and before the first cleavage of the zygote. This is the earliest expression of small RNAs ever described at a developmental stage long thought to be transcriptionally quiescent. A comparison of the two classes of Ascaris endo-siRNAs, 22G-RNAs and 26G-RNAs, to those in C. elegans, suggests great diversification and plasticity in the use of small RNA pathways during spermatogenesis in different nematodes. Our data reveal conserved characteristics of nematode small RNAs as well as features unique to Ascaris that illustrate significant flexibility in the use of small RNAs pathways, some of which are likely an adaptation to Ascaris’ life cycle and parasitism. Overall design: We constructed and analyzed 51 libraries from discrete regions of gametogenesis and synchronized stages of embryo development in the parasitic nematode Ascaris, using three types of small RNA libraries preparation methods: 1) 28 libraries of 18-34 or 18-40 nt RNAs with a 5’ monophosphate (5’ monophosphate libraries), 2) 4 libraries of 18-34 nt RNAs with a 5’ monophosphate but treated with periodate to enrich for small RNAs with 3’ end modifications (5’ monophosphate, 3’ end modified), and 3) 19 libraries of 18-28 or 18-40 nt RNAs with a 5’ triphosphate, diphosphate, or monophosphate (5’ allphosphate). These libraries enabled us to identify different small RNAs, characterize their different 5’ and 3’ ends, and their expression profiles through gametogenesis and embryogenesis.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>6253</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Ascaris suum</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA12863"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA136965"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>PUBMED</DB>
        <ID>21685128</ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA142039&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA142039&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>142039</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2013-05-31</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA142041" alias="PRJNA142041" center_name="Richard E. Davis Lab, Biochemistry and Molecular Genetics, University of Colorado Denver" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA142041</PRIMARY_ID>
    <EXTERNAL_ID namespace="GEO">GSE26956</EXTERNAL_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="Richard E. Davis Lab, Biochemistry and Molecular Genetics, University of Colorado Denver">PRJNA142041</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Ascaris suum</NAME>
  <TITLE>Ascaris suum transcriptome (RNA-Seq) data</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>Eukaryotic cells express several classes of small RNAs that regulate gene expression and ensure genome maintenance. Endogenous siRNAs (endo-siRNAs) and Piwi-interacting RNAs (piRNAs) mainly control gene and transposon expression in the germline, while microRNAs (miRNAs) generally function in post-transcriptional gene silencing in both somatic and germline cells. To provide an evolutionary and developmental perspective on small RNA pathways in nematodes, we identified and characterized known and novel small RNA classes through gametogenesis and embryo development in the parasitic nematode Ascaris suum and compared them with known small RNAs of Caenorhabditis elegans. piRNAs, Piwi-clade Argonautes, and other proteins associated with the piRNA pathway have been lost in Ascaris. miRNAs are synthesized immediately following fertilization in utero, prior to pronuclear fusion, and before the first cleavage of the zygote. This is the earliest expression of small RNAs ever described at a developmental stage long thought to be transcriptionally quiescent. A comparison of the two classes of Ascaris endo-siRNAs, 22G-RNAs and 26G-RNAs, to those in C. elegans, suggests great diversification and plasticity in the use of small RNA pathways during spermatogenesis in different nematodes. Our data reveal conserved characteristics of nematode small RNAs as well as features unique to Ascaris that illustrate significant flexibility in the use of small RNAs pathways, some of which are likely an adaptation to Ascaris’ life cycle and parasitism. Overall design: We generated transcriptomes from Ascaris germline and embryos for de-novo assembly as well as cDNA expression profiles. Two types of libraries were prepared: 1) sheared, full-length cDNA synthesized using a combination of oligo-dT and random hexamer priming and 2) cDNA prepared from RNA first chemically sheared and then double-stranded cDNA prepared using ramom hexamer priming.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>6253</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Ascaris suum</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA12863"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA136965"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>PUBMED</DB>
        <ID>21685128</ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA142041&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA142041&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>142041</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2013-05-31</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA153609" alias="PRJNA153609" center_name="The Genome Institute" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA153609</PRIMARY_ID>
    <EXTERNAL_ID namespace="GEO">GSE36690</EXTERNAL_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="The Genome Institute">PRJNA153609</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Ascaris suum</NAME>
  <TITLE>Gene expression analysis distinguishes tissue specific and gender related functions among adult Ascaris suum tissues.</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>Over a billion people are infected by Ascaris spp. intestinal parasites. We investigated gene expression by various tissues of adult A. suum, and used that information to help resolve basic functions of these tissues, basic biology of parasitism and functional aspects of nematode genomes. The A. suum genome was sequenced and assembled to allow generation of microarray elements. Expression of over 40,000 60-mer elements was investigated in a variety of tissues from both male and female adult worms. Nearly 50 percent of the elements for which signal was detected exhibited differential expression among different tissues. The unique profile of transcripts identified for each tissue clarified functional distinctions among tissues, such as chitin binding in the ovary and peptidase activity in the intestines. Interestingly, hundreds of gender specific elements characterized female or male intestinal tissues, respectively. A. suum genes from the same family were frequently expressed differently among tissues. Transcript abundance for genes specific to A. suum, by comparison to Caenorhabditis elegans, varied to a greater extent among tissues than for genes conserved between A. suum and C. elegans. Analysis using C. elegans protein interaction data identified functional modules conserved between these two nematodes, resulting in identification of functional predictions of essential subnetworks of protein interactions and how these networks may vary among nematode tissues. A notable finding was very high module similarity between adult reproductive tissues and intestine. Our data identified gene and predicted protein determinants that distinguish functions of individual adult A. suum tissues as well those that likely serve all the tissues investigated in our study. The size of A. suum adults (30-40 cm compared to less than 1 cm for many nematodes) enabled this resolution and will facilitate experimental dissection of individual and interactive functions of these tissues in this and other parasitic nematodes. Overall design: 10 samples were prepared from the tissues of adult worms of both genders to be analyzed. Two to three replicates were done for each sample, swapping dyes and channel for the test and the control for each sample. The control consisted of pooled worm tissues from both genders with an equal amount being included from each sample. These samples and the control were hybridized against an Agilent 4x44k format custom chip spotted with 42,212 probes. This probeset was created from 38,768 predicted protein coding sequences from an Ascaris suum genome survey sequence (GSS) project, and also from 5,176 EST contigs that were not covered by this predicted GSS gene-set. These 43,944 putative gene sequences from Ascaris suum were filtered for cross-reaction to non-coding sequences using Agilent eArray, and our final set of 42,212 probes was determined.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>6253</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Ascaris suum</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA12863"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA286848"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>PUBMED</DB>
        <ID>23572074</ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA153609&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA153609&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>153609</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2014-02-11</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA167264" alias="PRJNA167264" center_name="The Genome Institute" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA167264</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="The Genome Institute">PRJNA167264</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Ascaris suum</NAME>
  <TITLE>De novo nematode genome sequencing project to sequence, Ascaris suum, or Pig Roundworm.</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>Ascaris species are the largest intestinal worms and responsible for ascariasis, the commonest helminth infection of humans worldwide. Adult Ascaris live in the small intestine, where each female can produce hundreds of thousands of eggs each day. Eggs are passed into the environment where, over about 10 days, they develop into larvae. This takes place in the soil, thus Ascaris (along with hookworms and whipworms) are classified as soil-transmitted helminths. Human infections are common in sub-tropical and tropical areas with poor sanitation and are predominantly due to the species A. lumbricoides. A closely related species A. suum typically infects pigs.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>6253</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Ascaris suum</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA12863"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA286848"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA167264&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA167264&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>167264</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2013-05-31</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA168099" alias="PRJNA168099" center_name="Richard E. Davis Lab, Biochemistry and Molecular Genetics, University of Colorado Denver" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA168099</PRIMARY_ID>
    <EXTERNAL_ID namespace="GEO">GSE38470</EXTERNAL_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="Richard E. Davis Lab, Biochemistry and Molecular Genetics, University of Colorado Denver">PRJNA168099</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Ascaris suum</NAME>
  <TITLE>Silencing of Germline-Expressed Genes by DNA Elimination in Somatic Cells</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>Chromatin diminution is the programmed elimination of specific DNA sequences during development. It occurs in diverse species, but the function(s) of diminution and the specificity of sequence loss remain largely unknown. Diminution in the nematode Ascaris suum occurs during early embryonic cleavages and leads to the loss of germline genome sequences and the formation of a distinct genome in somatic cells. We found that ∼43 Mb (∼13%) of genome sequence is eliminated in A. suum somatic cells, including ∼12.7 Mb of unique sequence. The eliminated sequences and location of the DNA breaks are the same in all somatic lineages from a single individual and between different individuals. At least 685 genes are eliminated. These genes are preferentially expressed in the germline and during early embryogenesis. We propose that diminution is a mechanism of germline gene regulation that specifically removes a large number of genes involved in gametogenesis and early embryogenesis. Overall design: To profile the tissue expression of all A. suum genes, we used 8 different developmental stages/tissues of A. suum, including testis, ovary, embryo, larvae, intestine, muscle, male carcass and female carcass. In this submission there are 10 samples: 3 for early embryos (24hr, 46hr and 64hr) and the other 7 for testis, ovary, larvae, intestine, muscle, male carcass and female carcass. For each sample, 200 ug of total RNA was used for poly(A) selection and 200 ng of poly(A)+ RNA was used to make the cDNA libraries using standard Illumina protocol.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>6253</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Ascaris suum</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA12863"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>PUBMED</DB>
        <ID>23123092</ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA168099&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA168099&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>168099</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2013-05-31</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA176555" alias="PRJNA176555" center_name="Translational Research Sciences, Hoffmann-LaRoche" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA176555</PRIMARY_ID>
    <EXTERNAL_ID namespace="GEO">GSE41329</EXTERNAL_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="Translational Research Sciences, Hoffmann-LaRoche">PRJNA176555</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Macaca fascicularis</NAME>
  <TITLE>Blockade of thymic stromal lymphopoietin receptor (TSLPR) reduces allergic inflammation in a cynomolgus monkey model of asthma</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>TSLP pathway blockade is a potential strategy for asthma treatment, as TSLP modulates cytokine production by mast cells and regulates the activation of dendritic cells (DCs), which prime the differentiation of naïve T cells into inflammatory Th2 cells. To assess the effect of TSLPR blockade on the development of allergic inflammation and bronchoconstriction in Cynomolgus monkeys after Ascaris suum allergen challenge. Antibodies against human TSLPR were generated and confirmed to be cross-reactive to cynomolgus. Animals were dosed weekly with either vehicle (n=8) or TSLPR HuMAb (n=8) for 6 weeks and their responses to A.Suum challenge at baseline, week 2 and week 6 were assessed. Antibody-treated animals showed reduced bronchoalveolar lavage (BAL) eosinophil counts (p=0.04), reduced lung resistance (RL) area under the curve (p=0.04), and reduced IL-13 cytokine levels in BAL fluid (p=0.03) in response to challenge at 6 weeks compared to vehicle-treated animals. To understand the molecular changes underlying these differences, BAL fluid samples pre- and post-challenge were profiled using microarrays. Genes up-regulated by allergen challenge overlapped strongly with 11 genes up-regulated in DCs when stimulated by TSLP (TSLP-DC signature). The number of genes differentially expressed in response to challenge was reduced in aTSLPR-treated animals after 6 weeks relative to vehicle-treated animals. Expression of the TSLP-DC gene signature was also significantly reduced in aTSLPR-treated animals (p = 0.05). These results demonstrate promising efficacy for TSLPR blockade in an allergen challenge model where TSLP activation of DCs may play a key role. Overall design: Animals were dosed weekly with either vehicle (n=8) or TSLPR HuMAb (n=8) for 6 weeks and their responses to A.Suum challenge at baseline, week 2 and week 6 were assessed. One monkey in the aTSLPR-treated group expired during the study for reasons not linked to drug safety and tolerability. BAL fluid samples for all animals were subject to gene expression profiling for pre-challenge, 8h and 24h post-challenge timepoints, at baseline, week 2 and week 6. This amounted to a total of 135 microarrays. Data from 8 animals were excluded as outliers, determined by PCA.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>9541</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Macaca fascicularis</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA20403"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>PUBMED</DB>
        <ID>23810153</ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA176555&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA176555&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>176555</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2014-02-11</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA177909" alias="PRJNA177909" center_name="Translational Research Sciences, Hoffmann-LaRoche" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA177909</PRIMARY_ID>
    <EXTERNAL_ID namespace="GEO">GSE41668</EXTERNAL_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="Translational Research Sciences, Hoffmann-LaRoche">PRJNA177909</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Macaca fascicularis</NAME>
  <TITLE>Poly I:C Induced Gene Expression Changes in Non-Human Primates II</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>The respiratory epithelium is the body’s first line of defense to pathogens, pollutants, and other potentially injurious agents that can be inhaled. Sampling the upper respiratory tract is becoming a widely used technique in the clinic to examine the molecular changes in the diseased airway; however, it is unclear as to whether the responses in the upper respiratory tract (i.e. the nasal turbinates) reflect the changes that occur in the lower respiratory tract (i.e. trachea and lungs). Here, we assessed the responses to poly I:C, a synthetic double-stranded RNA molecule that is meant to mimic the acute effects of a viral infection, in both the upper and lower respiratory tracts of cynomolgus macaques. To do this, we compared the in vivo response after a nasal poly I:C challenge in a nasal scrape samples (performed using a nasal curette) to responses that occurred after ex vivo poly I:C stimulation in nasal scrapes, tracheal epithelial brushings, and lung tissue explants in non-human primates. Overall design: Animals were sedated with ketamine (10-15 mg/kg) delivered i.m. For nasal scrapes, a nasal curette was used to take a sample from the nasal cavity (blind, but likely to be from the inferior/maxilloturbinate). Repeated sampling in NHPs sensitized (n = 4) and not sensitized (n =3) to Ascaris suum occurred at baseline (0h), 6h, 24h and 72h time points.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>9541</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Macaca fascicularis</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA20403"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA177909&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA177909&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>177909</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2015-10-11</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA198514" alias="PRJNA198514" center_name="Richard E. Davis Lab, Biochemistry and Molecular Genetics, University of Colorado Denver" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA198514</PRIMARY_ID>
    <EXTERNAL_ID namespace="GEO">GSE46277</EXTERNAL_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="Richard E. Davis Lab, Biochemistry and Molecular Genetics, University of Colorado Denver">PRJNA198514</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Ascaris suum</NAME>
  <TITLE>Transcription in Pronuclei and One- to Four-Cell Embryos Drives Early Development in a Nematode</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>A long-standing view of development is that transcription is silenced in the oocyte until early divisions in the embryo. The point at which major transcription is reactivated varies in different organisms, but is usually after the 2-cell stage. However, this model may not be universal. We used RNA-seq and exploited the protracted development of the parasitic nematode Ascaris suum, to provide a comprehensive time course of mRNA expression, degradation, and translation during early development. Surprisingly, we find that ~4,000 genes are transcribed prior to pronuclear fusion and in the 1-4 cell embryos. Intriguingly, we do not detect maternal contribution of many orthologs of maternal C. elegans mRNAs, but instead find these are newly transcribed in the A. suum zygote prior to pronuclear fusion. Ribosome profiling demonstrates that, in general, early embryonic mRNAs are not stored for subsequent translation, but are directly translated following their synthesis. The role of maternally contributed and zygotically transcribed genes differs between the nematodes A. suum and C. elegans despite the fact that the two nematodes appear to exhibit highly similar morphological patterns during early development. Our study indicates that major transcription can occur immediately after fertilization and prior to pronuclear fusion in metazoa, suggesting that newly transcribed genes appear to drive A. suum early development. Furthermore, the mechanisms used for controlling the timing of the expression of key conserved genes has been altered between the two nematodes, illustrating significant plasticity in the regulatory networks that play important roles in developmental outcomes in nematodes. Overall design: A total of 28 samples are used for this study. The RNAs for the library construction are derived from 0.5 – 1 ml of synchronized embryo stages corresponding to a minimum of 0.5 billion embryos derived from > 1,000 female worms. The RNAs for polysome analysis are from pooled fractions of polysome gradient. For each sample, the amount of RNA for all polysome fractions is equivalent to the total RNA from the sample. Thus, the data from polysome profiling and RNA transcriptomes are considered as biological replicates. The level of the RNAs between each neighboring stages during development are considered as the reference for each other. Different sequencing strategies were applied for multiple libraries.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>6253</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Ascaris suum</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA12863"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>PUBMED</DB>
        <ID>24374308</ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA198514&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA198514&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>198514</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2014-01-04</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA230513" alias="PRJNA230513" center_name="The Genome Institute" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA230513</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="The Genome Institute">PRJNA230513</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Ascaris lumbricoides</NAME>
  <TITLE>Ascaris lumbricoides Genome sequencing</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>Ascaris lumbricoides is the giant roundworm of humans, belonging to the phylum Nematoda. An ascarid nematode, it is responsible for the disease ascariasis in humans, and it is the largest and most common parasitic worm in humans. One sixth of the human population is estimated to be infected by Ascaris lumbricoides or another roundworm. Ascariasis is prevalent worldwide and more so in tropical and subtropical countries.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT>
      <LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>X799</LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>
    </SEQUENCING_PROJECT>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>6252</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Ascaris lumbricoides</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA77195"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA230513&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA230513&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>230513</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2013-12-12</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA286848" alias="PRJNA286848" center_name="McDonnell Genome Institute" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA286848</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="McDonnell Genome Institute">PRJNA286848</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Ascaris suum</NAME>
  <TITLE>Ascaris suum genome sequencing, assembly and analysis.</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>Ascaris species are the largest intestinal worms and responsible for ascariasis, the commonest helminth infection of humans worldwide. Adult Ascaris live in the small intestine, where each female can produce hundreds of thousands of eggs each day. Eggs are passed into the environment where, over about 10 days, they develop into larvae. This takes place in the soil, thus Ascaris (along with hookworms and whipworms) are classified as soil-transmitted helminths. Human infections are common in sub-tropical and tropical areas with poor sanitation and are predominantly due to the species A. lumbricoides. A closely related species A. suum typically infects pigs</DESCRIPTION>
  <UMBRELLA_PROJECT/>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <CHILD_PROJECT accession="PRJNA12864"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <CHILD_PROJECT accession="PRJNA153609"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <CHILD_PROJECT accession="PRJNA167264"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA12863"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA286848&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA286848&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>286848</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>UMBRELLA</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2015-06-14</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA303092" alias="PRJNA303092" center_name="Indian agricultural research institute" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA303092</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="Indian agricultural research institute">PRJNA303092</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Heterorhabditis indica isolate:IJ</NAME>
  <TITLE>Heterorhabditis indica isolate:IJ Assembly</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>Nematodes are the most numerous animals in soil. Insect parasitic nematodes of the genus Heterorhabditis are capable of selectively seeking, infecting and killing their insect hosts in soil. The infective juvenile (IJ) stage of the Heterorhabditis nematodes is analogous to Caenorhabditis elegans dauer juvenile stage, which remains in ‘arrested development’ till it finds and infects a new insect-host in soil. H. indica is the most prevalent species of Heterorhabditis in India. To understand the genes and molecular processes that govern the the biology of the IJ stage of H. indica, and to create the foundation for genetic exploration of H. indica, we sequenced the transcriptome of H. indica IJs. The de-novo sequence assembly using velvet - oases pipeline resulted in 18,710 contigs with N50 of 909 bp. However, after using cd-hit-est and filtering out &lt;300bp transcripts, 13,592 unique transcripts were identified, and N50 increased to 1371. Orthologs of the genes expressing in IJ stage of the H indica were identified by comparing these 13,592 protein sequences with complete genomes of other closely related rhabditid nematodes through reciprocal blast approach which revealed 3364 orthologs with C. elegans, 3103 with C. briggsae, 2164 with Pristionchus pacificus, 346 with H. bacteriophora, and 3171 orthologs with C. remanei. Further, H. indica transcriptome was compared with the available plant, animal and human parasitic nematode genome sequences. We found 9906 and 8892 protein matches with Meloidogyne hapla and M. incognita respectively, 9685 with Ascaris suum, 9051 with Brugia malayi, 8188 with Strongyloides ratti and 7588 with Trichinella spiralis. Similar to C. elegans, all the four dauer formation pathways - cGMP - PKG signaling pathway, Insulin signaling pathway, Dafachronic acid pathway and TGF-β are were conserved and active in the IJ stage H. indica. Several important signaling pathways were found active in the IJs indicating that in-spite of being a developmentally arrested stage, IJs are a hot bed of signalling and are actively interacting with their environment. Similarly, glycolysis and fatty acid degradation pathways were highly active in IJs indicating breakdown of food reserves. Twenty four orthologs of C. elegans RNAi pathway effector genes were found in H. indica IJ transcriptome, including nrde-3 which has been identified for the first time in any of the parasitic worms.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>51550</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Heterorhabditis indica</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA293772"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA303092&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA303092&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>303092</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2015-11-23</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA304165" alias="PRJNA304165" center_name="Smith College" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA304165</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="Smith College">PRJNA304165</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Soil Transmitted Helminths</NAME>
  <TITLE>Necator americanus, Ascaris lumbricoides, Trichuris trichiura, Ancylostoma duodenale raw sequence reads</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>Sequencing aims to discover highly repetitive sequences within each organism. These sequences can be used for diagnostic development and evolutionary relationship characterization</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA304165&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA304165&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>304165</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2015-12-02</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2023-05-17</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA308932" alias="PRJNA308932" center_name="Richard E. Davis Lab, Biochemistry and Molecular Genetics, University of Colorado Denver" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA308932</PRIMARY_ID>
    <EXTERNAL_ID namespace="GEO">GSE76914</EXTERNAL_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="Richard E. Davis Lab, Biochemistry and Molecular Genetics, University of Colorado Denver">PRJNA308932</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Ascaris suum</NAME>
  <TITLE>Differential Chromosomal Localization of Centromeric Histone CENP-A Contributes to Nematode Programmed DNA Elimination</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>The stability of the genome is paramount to organisms. However, diverse eukaryotes carry out programmed DNA elimination in which portions or entire chromsomes are lost in early development or during sex determination. During early development of the parasitic nematode, Ascaris suum, 13% of the genome is eliminated. How different genomic segments are reproducibly retained or discarded is unknown. Here, we show that centromeric histone CENP-A localization plays a key role in this process. We show that Ascaris chromosomes are holocentric during germline mitoses, with CENP-A distributed along their length. Prior to DNA elimination in the four-cell embryo, CENP-A is significantly diminished in chromosome regions that will be lost. This leads to the absence of kinetochores and microtubule attachment sites necessary for chromosome segregation, resulting in loss of these regions upon mitosis. Our data suggest that changes in CENP-A localization specify which portions of chromosomes will be lost during programmed DNA elimination. Overall design: A total of 62 samples are analyzed. These include: (1). CENP-A ChIP-seq on 12 developmental stages with input and replicates (12 x 2 x 2 samples); (2). CENP-C ChIP-seq on 3 developmental stages with input and replicates (total 8 samples); and (3). Histone marks ChIP-seq with 6 samples</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>6253</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Ascaris suum</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA12863"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>PUBMED</DB>
        <ID>27545882</ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA308932&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA308932&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>308932</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2016-07-16</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA388698" alias="PRJNA388698" center_name="Richard E. Davis Lab, Biochemistry and Molecular Genetics, University of Colorado Denver" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA388698</PRIMARY_ID>
    <EXTERNAL_ID namespace="GEO">GSE99524</EXTERNAL_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="Richard E. Davis Lab, Biochemistry and Molecular Genetics, University of Colorado Denver">PRJNA388698</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Parascaris univalens</NAME>
  <TITLE>Comparative Genome Analysis of Programmed DNA Elimination in Nematodes (Parascaris)</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>Programmed DNA elimination is a developmentally regulated process leading to the reproducible loss of specific genomic sequences. DNA elimination occurs in unicellular ciliates and a variety of metazoans, including invertebrates and vertebrates. In metazoa, DNA elimination typically occurs in somatic cells during early development, leaving the germline genome intact. Reference genomes for metazoa that undergo DNA elimination are not available. Here, we generated germline and somatic reference genome sequences of the DNA eliminating pig parasitic nematode Ascaris suum and the horse parasite Parascaris univalens. In addition, we carried out in-depth analyses of DNA elimination in the parasitic nematode of humans, Ascaris lumbricoides, and the parasitic nematode of dogs, Toxocara canis. Our analysis of nematode DNA elimination reveals that in all species, repetitive sequences (that differ among the genera) and germline-expressed genes (approximately 1000-2000 or 5%-10% of the genes) are eliminated. Thirty-five percent of these eliminated genes are conserved among these nematodes, defining a core set of eliminated genes that are preferentially expressed during spermatogenesis. Our analysis supports the view that DNA elimination in nematodes silences germline-expressed genes. Over half of the chromosome break sites are conserved between Ascaris and Parascaris, whereas only 10% are conserved in the more divergent T. canis. Analysis of the chromosomal breakage regions suggests a sequence-independent mechanism for DNA breakage followed by telomere healing, with the formation of more accessible chromatin in the break regions prior to DNA elimination. Our genome assemblies and annotations also provide comprehensive resources for analysis of DNA elimination, parasitology research, and comparative nematode genome and epigenome studies. Overall design: A total of 6 samples are used for this study, including male germline, female germline, embryo, intestine and carcass, and a mixed sample for 5'-end RNA sequencing.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>6257</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Parascaris univalens</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA386832"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>PUBMED</DB>
        <ID>29118011</ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA388698&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA388698&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>388698</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2017-08-18</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA388699" alias="PRJNA388699" center_name="Richard E. Davis Lab, Biochemistry and Molecular Genetics, University of Colorado Denver" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA388699</PRIMARY_ID>
    <EXTERNAL_ID namespace="GEO">GSE99523</EXTERNAL_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="Richard E. Davis Lab, Biochemistry and Molecular Genetics, University of Colorado Denver">PRJNA388699</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Ascaris suum</NAME>
  <TITLE>Comparative Genome Analysis of Programmed DNA Elimination in Nematodes (Ascaris)</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>Programmed DNA elimination is a developmentally regulated process leading to the reproducible loss of specific genomic sequences. DNA elimination occurs in unicellular ciliates and a variety of metazoans, including invertebrates and vertebrates. In metazoa, DNA elimination typically occurs in somatic cells during early development, leaving the germline genome intact. Reference genomes for metazoa that undergo DNA elimination are not available. Here, we generated germline and somatic reference genome sequences of the DNA eliminating pig parasitic nematode Ascaris suum and the horse parasite Parascaris univalens. In addition, we carried out in-depth analyses of DNA elimination in the parasitic nematode of humans, Ascaris lumbricoides, and the parasitic nematode of dogs, Toxocara canis. Our analysis of nematode DNA elimination reveals that in all species, repetitive sequences (that differ among the genera) and germline-expressed genes (approximately 1000-2000 or 5%-10% of the genes) are eliminated. Thirty-five percent of these eliminated genes are conserved among these nematodes, defining a core set of eliminated genes that are preferentially expressed during spermatogenesis. Our analysis supports the view that DNA elimination in nematodes silences germline-expressed genes. Over half of the chromosome break sites are conserved between Ascaris and Parascaris, whereas only 10% are conserved in the more divergent T. canis. Analysis of the chromosomal breakage regions suggests a sequence-independent mechanism for DNA breakage followed by telomere healing, with the formation of more accessible chromatin in the break regions prior to DNA elimination. Our genome assemblies and annotations also provide comprehensive resources for analysis of DNA elimination, parasitology research, and comparative nematode genome and epigenome studies. Overall design: A total of 11 Ascaris samples are used for this study, including regions of the male germline (1, mitotic region; 2, spermatogenesis; 3, post-meiotic region; 4, seminal vesicle; and 5, spermatids), regions of the female germline (1, mitotic region; 2, early pachytene; 3, late pachytene; 4, diplotene; and 5, oocyte), and a mixed sample for 5'-end SL and TeloPrime RNA-seq.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>6253</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Ascaris suum</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA12863"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>PUBMED</DB>
        <ID>29118011</ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA388699&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA388699&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>388699</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2017-08-18</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA391703" alias="PRJNA391703" center_name="aph" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA391703</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="aph">PRJNA391703</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Ascaris lumbricoides strain:nematoda | isolate:Ascaridida | breed:eukaryotic | cultivar:Secernentea</NAME>
  <TITLE>Ascaris lumbricoides strain:nematoda | isolate:Ascaridida | breed:eukaryotic | cultivar:Secernentea</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>Ascaris lumbricoides, a roundworm, infects humans when an ingested fertilised egg becomes a larval worm (called rhabditiform larva) that penetrates the wall of the duodenum and enters the blood stream. From there, it is carried to the liver and heart, and enters pulmonary circulation to break free in the alveoli, where it grows and molts. In three weeks, the larva passes from the respiratory system to be coughed up, swallowed, and thus returned to the small intestine, where it matures to an adult male or female worm. Fertilization can now occur and the female produces as many as 200,000 eggs per day for a year. These fertilized eggs become infectious after two weeks in soil; they can persist in soil for 10 years or more</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>6252</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Ascaris lumbricoides</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
      <STRAIN>nematoda</STRAIN>
      <BREED>eukaryotic</BREED>
      <CULTIVAR>Secernentea</CULTIVAR>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA77195"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>PUBMED</DB>
        <ID>434343</ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA391703&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA391703&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>391703</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2017-06-25</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA399179" alias="PRJNA399179" center_name="University of Copenhagen" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA399179</PRIMARY_ID>
    <EXTERNAL_ID namespace="GEO">GSE102895</EXTERNAL_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="University of Copenhagen">PRJNA399179</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Homo sapiens</NAME>
  <TITLE>Modulation of human dendritic cell (DC) activity by Ascaris suum body fluid or cocoa procyanidins</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>The hypothesis was that A. suum body fluid or cocoa procyandins downregulate LPS-induced inflammatory pathways in human DCs Overall design: DCs were cultured with either LPS, LPS with PC or LPS with A. suum adult body fluid for 6 hours</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>9606</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Homo sapiens</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA9558"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>PUBMED</DB>
        <ID>29136163</ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA399179&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA399179&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>399179</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2018-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA408234" alias="PRJNA408234" center_name="University of Copenhagen" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA408234</PRIMARY_ID>
    <EXTERNAL_ID namespace="GEO">GSE104092</EXTERNAL_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="University of Copenhagen">PRJNA408234</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Expression data from mucosa of pigs</NAME>
  <TITLE>Expression data from mucosa of pigs</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>We aimed to determine the infect of Ascaris suum infection on mucosal immune pathways in pigs Overall design: Pigs were infected or not with Ascaris suum. At days 56 post-infection the jejunum mucosa was sampled for microarray analysis</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>9823</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Sus scrofa</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA10718"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>PUBMED</DB>
        <ID>29136163</ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA408234&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA408234&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>408234</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2018-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA450204" alias="PRJNA450204" center_name="Robert Koch Insitute" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA450204</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="Robert Koch Insitute">PRJNA450204</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <TITLE>Dual RNA-Seq of Ascaris suum larvae (L3) and Sus scrofa cells (IPEC-J2)</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>A time-resolved interaction model of porcine intestinal epithelial cells (IPEC-J2) and infective Ascaris suum larvae to address the early transcriptional changes occurring in both organisms simultaneously using dual-species RNA-Seq.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA450204&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA450204&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>450204</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2018-04-22</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2023-05-19</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA510835" alias="PRJNA510835" center_name="NIAID Bioinformatics and Computational Biosciences Branch" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA510835</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="NIAID Bioinformatics and Computational Biosciences Branch">PRJNA510835</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <TITLE>The impact of anthelmintic treatment on human gut microbiota in western Kenya: Cross-sectional and pre-post deworming comparisons</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>Murine studies suggest that the presence of some species of intestinal helminths is associated with changes in host microbiota composition and diversity. Some changes are even found in anatomic locations remote from where these helminths reside and may persist after helminth clearance. However, studies in humans have produced varied conclusions and the impact appears to vary widely depending on the helminth species present. To demonstrate how molecular approaches to the human gut microbiome can provide insights into the complex interplay among disparate organisms, DNA was extracted from cryopreserved stools collected from residents of 5 rural Kenyan villages prior to, 3 weeks and 3 months following albendazole (ALB) therapy. Samples were analyzed by qPCR for the presence of 8 species of intestinal parasites, and by MiSeq 16S rRNA gene sequencing. Based on pre-treatment results, the presence of neither Ascaris lumbricoides (Al) nor Necator americanus (Na) infection significantly altered the overall diversity of the microbiota in comparison with age-matched controls. Following ALB therapy and clearance of soil-transmitted helminths (STH), there were significant increases in the proportion of the microbiota made up by Clostridiales (p=0.0002, average fold change 0.57), and reductions in the proportion made up by Enterobacteriales (p=0.0004, average fold change -0.58). There were additional changes in the microbiota that appear to be related to ALB administration, suggesting that these antimicrobial effects must be considered in any post-treatment setting. Nevertheless, the helminth-associated changes in Clostridiales and Enterobacteriales suggest that clearance of STH, and Na in particular, alters the gut microbiota. This submission was done on behalf of Thomas B. Nutman (Principal Investigator) and Alice V. Easton.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA510835&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA510835&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>510835</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2019-01-03</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2023-05-17</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA511012" alias="PRJNA511012" center_name="NIAID" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA511012</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="NIAID">PRJNA511012</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Ascaris lumbricoides</NAME>
  <TITLE>Ascaris lumbricoides Raw sequence reads</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>68 Ascaris lumbricoides WGS reads from Bungoma County, Kenya</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>6252</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Ascaris lumbricoides</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA77195"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA511012&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA511012&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>511012</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2019-06-04</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA511996" alias="PRJNA511996" center_name="NIAID" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA511996</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="NIAID">PRJNA511996</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Ascaris lumbricoides</NAME>
  <TITLE>Ascaris lumbricoides Raw sequence reads</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>Raw sequencing used for repeat analysis</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>6252</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Ascaris lumbricoides</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA77195"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA511996&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA511996&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>511996</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2019-06-07</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA515325" alias="PRJNA515325" center_name="NIAID" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA515325</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="NIAID">PRJNA515325</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Ascaris lumbricoides isolate:Kenyan</NAME>
  <TITLE>Ascaris lumbricoides isolate:Kenyan Genome sequencing and assembly</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>Reference quality genome assembly of Ascaris lumbricoides from the Bungoma region of Kenya</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT>
      <LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>E2970</LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>
      <LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>E2971</LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>
      <LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>ERJ42</LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>
      <LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>ERJ43</LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>
      <LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>ERJ44</LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>
      <LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>EX532</LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>
    </SEQUENCING_PROJECT>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>6252</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Ascaris lumbricoides</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA77195"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA515325&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA515325&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>515325</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2019-07-14</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA518084" alias="PRJNA518084" center_name="USDA" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA518084</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="USDA">PRJNA518084</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <TITLE>Characterization of the intestinal microbiome in pigs infected by the gastrointestinal nematode Ascaris suum</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>The effect of infection of pigs with Ascaris suum on the microbial composition in the proximal colon and fecal matters was investigated using 16S rRNA gene sequencing.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA518084&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA518084&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>518084</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2019-02-09</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2023-05-19</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA556423" alias="PRJNA556423" center_name="aph" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA556423</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="aph">PRJNA556423</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Ascaris lumbricoides strain:Nematode</NAME>
  <TITLE>Ascaris lumbricoides strain:Nematode Phenotype or Genotype</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>Ascaris nematode</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>6252</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Ascaris lumbricoides</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
      <STRAIN>Nematode</STRAIN>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA77195"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA556423&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA556423&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>556423</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2019-07-26</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA564834" alias="PRJNA564834" center_name="Department of Biotechnology and Biomedicine, Technical University of Denmark" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA564834</PRIMARY_ID>
    <EXTERNAL_ID namespace="GEO">GSE137229</EXTERNAL_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="Department of Biotechnology and Biomedicine, Technical University of Denmark">PRJNA564834</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Body fluid from the parasitic worm Ascaris suum inhibits broad-acting pro-inflammatory programs in dendritic cells</NAME>
  <TITLE>Body fluid from the parasitic worm Ascaris suum inhibits broad-acting pro-inflammatory programs in dendritic cells</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>Purpose: To characterize the processes defining the end dendritic cell (DC) phenotype, including the type of early transcriptional changes in pro-inflammatory cues towards regulatory or type 2 immune-based cues induced by a variety of exogenous and endogenous molecules. Methods: Human peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMCs) were isolated from buffy coats from human donors using Ficoll-Paque gradient centrifugation. CD14+ monocytes were isolated from PBMCs by magnetic-activated cell sorting (MACS) and cultured in complete medium consisting of RPMI 1640 supplemented with 10% heat-inactivated fetal bovine serum, 2 mM L-glutamine, 50 µM 2-Mercaptoethanol, 1% Penicillin-Streptomycin at 37°C and 5% CO2. During the differentiation stage, complete medium was added 150 U/mL recombinant human IL-4 and 160 U/mL recombinant human GM-CSF to obtain monocyte-derived dendritic cells (moDCs). Medium was replaced after 3 days of culturing, and moDCs were used 6 days after the start of culture. The cells were on average >70% CD1a-positive, and with &lt;3% CD14+CD16+ cells, based on flow cytometry, and responded with high levels of IL-12p70 production upon stimulation with LPS and IFN-y (mean IL-12p70 production of 4641.8 pg/mL; SD = 688.1 pg/mL). Cells were harvested and rested for 1 hour at 37°C and 5% CO2 before stimulation. At this point, moDCs were supplemented with complete medium containing TSLP (to final concentration of 25 ng/mL), IL-25 (25 ng/mL), TSLP+IL-25 (both 25 ng/mL), helminth PCF (100 μg dry matter/mL, tested in different doses in pre-study experiments), butyrate (2 mM), or succinate (0.5 mM and 2 mM, di-sodium succinate hexahydrate). Unstimulated cells were supplemented with complete medium alone. Immediately afterwards, medium containing Escherichia coli O26:B6 LPS (final concentration of 100 ng/mL) and IFN-γ (10 ng/mL) was added. Cells were stimulated for 4 or 20 h at 37°C, 5% CO2, and 95% humidity. Results: Our data show that helminth PCF and butyrate treatment suppress the Th1-inducing pro-inflammatory DC phenotype through induction of different transcriptional programs in DCs. RNA sequencing indicated that helminth PCF treatment strongly inhibited the Th1 and Th17 polarizing ability of LPS+IFN-γ-matured DCs by downregulating myeloid differentiation primary response gene 88 (MyD88)-dependent and MyD88-independent pathways in TLR4 signaling. By contrast, butyrate treatment had a strong Th1-inhibiting action, while transcripts encoding important gut barrier defending factors such as IL18, IL1B and CXCL8 were upregulated. Conclusion: Collectively, our results further our understanding of how compounds from parasites and gut microbiota-derived butyrate may exert immunomodulatory effects on the host immune system. Overall design: The transcriptional profile of stimulated human moDCs was evaluated, in triplicates, after 4 hours of stimulation. After stimulation for 20 hours, the cell-free culture supernatants were harvested and frozen at -80°C until further analysis. IL-12p70 levels were determined using ELISA in triplicates.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>9606</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Homo sapiens</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA9558"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>PUBMED</DB>
        <ID>31705653</ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA564834&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA564834&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>564834</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2019-09-20</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA62057" alias="PRJNA62057" center_name="Department of Biochemistry and Molecular Genetics, University of Colorado School of Medicine" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA62057</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="Department of Biochemistry and Molecular Genetics, University of Colorado School of Medicine">PRJNA62057</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Ascaris suum</NAME>
  <TITLE>Ascaris suum North American wild population, genome sequencing project</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>&lt;p>Chromatin diminution is the programmed elimination of specific DNA sequences during development. It occurs in diverse species, however, the function(s) of diminution and the specificity of sequence loss remain largely unknown. Diminution in the nematode &lt;i>Ascaris suum&lt;/i> occurs during early embryonic cleavages and leads to the loss of germline genome sequences and the formation of a distinct genome in somatic cells. We found that ~43 Mb (~13%) of genome sequence is eliminated in &lt;i>A. suum&lt;/i> somatic cells, including ~12.7 Mb of unique sequence. The eliminated sequences and location of the DNA breaks are the same in all somatic lineages from a single individual, and between different individuals. At least 685 genes are eliminated, and remarkably, these genes are preferentially expressed in the germline and during early embryogenesis. Our data demonstrate that diminution is an unprecedented mechanism of germline gene regulation that specifically removes a large number of genes involved in gametogenesis and early embryogenesis.  North American wild population</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT>
      <LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>AGW34</LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>
      <LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>AGW35</LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>
      <LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>ASU</LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>
      <LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>CR546</LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>
      <LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>CR547</LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>
      <LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>CR548</LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>
      <LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>CR549</LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>
      <LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>CR550</LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>
      <LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>CR551</LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>
      <LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>CR552</LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>
      <LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>CR553</LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>
      <LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>CR554</LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>
      <LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>HTY67</LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>
    </SEQUENCING_PROJECT>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>6253</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Ascaris suum</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA12863"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>PUBMED</DB>
        <ID>21685128</ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>PUBMED</DB>
        <ID>23123092</ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA62057&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA62057&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>62057</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2013-05-31</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA63155" alias="PRJNA63155" center_name="Department of Biochemistry and Molecular Genetics, University of Colorado School of Medicine" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA63155</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="Department of Biochemistry and Molecular Genetics, University of Colorado School of Medicine">PRJNA63155</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Ascaris suum</NAME>
  <TITLE>Ascaris suum North American wild population, Transcriptome Shotgun Assembly</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>&lt;p>This assembly represents a combination of transcripts from different developmental stages of Ascaris. Thus, six libraries from embryo, larvae, testis, ovary, complete female reproductive system, and whole males were prepared.  Reads from each of the 6 cDNA libraries were initially assembled with Velvet (Zerbino and Birney 2008). A set of reference sequences were built by combining all these assemblies together (phrap), and each library was reassembled (with Velvet) to obtain an improved assembly. Thus, an improved reference sequence was built, and this cycle was iterated until no further improvement could be achieved. The final assembly was improved by scaffolding and by experimental verification on genes of interest.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>6253</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Ascaris suum</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA12863"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>PUBMED</DB>
        <ID>21685128</ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA63155&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA63155&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>63155</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2013-05-31</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA673292" alias="PRJNA673292" center_name="Institute of Microbiology, Chinese Academy of Sciences" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA673292</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="Institute of Microbiology, Chinese Academy of Sciences">PRJNA673292</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Ascaris ovis</NAME>
  <TITLE>Ascaris ovis Genome sequencing and assembly</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>This project is to sequence and assembly the whole genome of sheep roundworm Ascaris ovis.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT>
      <LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>IRT40</LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>
    </SEQUENCING_PROJECT>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>1885273</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Ascaris ovis</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA673546"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA673292&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA673292&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>673292</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2020-11-02</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA673546" alias="PRJNA673546" center_name="NCBI" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA673546</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="NCBI">PRJNA673546</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Ascaris ovis</NAME>
  <TITLE>Ascaris ovis overview</TITLE>
  <UMBRELLA_PROJECT>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>1885273</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Ascaris ovis</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </UMBRELLA_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <CHILD_PROJECT accession="PRJNA673292"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA673546&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA673546&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>673546</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>ORGANISM</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2020-11-02</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA69809" alias="PRJNA69809" center_name="Institute of Biophysics, Chinese Academy of Sciences" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA69809</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="Institute of Biophysics, Chinese Academy of Sciences">PRJNA69809</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Ascaris suum</NAME>
  <TITLE>Comparative 454 pyrosequencing of Germline and Somatic Tissues of the Ascaris suum Gonad</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>submitted to BMC Genomics</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>6253</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Ascaris suum</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA12863"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA69809&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA69809&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>69809</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2013-05-31</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA714131" alias="PRJNA714131" center_name="University of Copenhagen" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA714131</PRIMARY_ID>
    <EXTERNAL_ID namespace="GEO">GSE168840</EXTERNAL_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="University of Copenhagen">PRJNA714131</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>RNA-sequencing data of lung tissue of pigs infected with parasites and adminstered proanthocyanidins (PAC)</NAME>
  <TITLE>RNA-sequencing data of lung tissue of pigs infected with parasites and adminstered proanthocyanidins (PAC)</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>We show here the transcriptional response in the lung of pigs infected or not with Ascaris suum, fed either a control pr a PAC-enriched diet Overall design: RNA was obtained from the lungs of 12 pigs infected with A. suum and 12 uninfected pigs. Within each infection group, pigs were fed either a control diet or the control diet supplemented with 1 % PAC derived from grape seed</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>9823</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Sus scrofa</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA10718"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>PUBMED</DB>
        <ID>35333423</ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA714131&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA714131&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>714131</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2021-06-02</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA728051" alias="PRJNA728051" center_name="University of Copenhagen" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA728051</PRIMARY_ID>
    <EXTERNAL_ID namespace="GEO">GSE174042</EXTERNAL_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="University of Copenhagen">PRJNA728051</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>RNA-sequencing data of intestinal tissue of pigs infected with parasites and adminstered proanthocyanidins (PAC)</NAME>
  <TITLE>RNA-sequencing data of intestinal tissue of pigs infected with parasites and adminstered proanthocyanidins (PAC)</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>We show here the transcriptional response in the intestine of pigs infected or not with Ascaris suum, fed either a control pr a PAC-enriched diet Overall design: RNA was obtained from the jejunum of 12 pigs infected with A. suum and 12 uninfected pigs. Within each infection group, pigs were fed either a control diet or the control diet supplemented with 1 % PAC derived from grape seed</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>9823</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Sus scrofa</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA10718"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>PUBMED</DB>
        <ID>35333423</ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA728051&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA728051&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>728051</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2021-05-10</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA750737" alias="PRJNA750737" center_name="Iowa State University" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA750737</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="Iowa State University">PRJNA750737</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Ascaris suum strain:wild type</NAME>
  <TITLE>Ascaris suum circRNA sequencing</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>Targeted RNA-seq for circRNAs in Ascaris suum genome</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>6253</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Ascaris suum</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
      <STRAIN>wild type</STRAIN>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA12863"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA750737&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA750737&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>750737</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2022-02-11</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA753018" alias="PRJNA753018" center_name="University of Copenhagen" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA753018</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="University of Copenhagen">PRJNA753018</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <TITLE>Dietary proanthocyanidins exert localized immunomodulatory effects in porcine pulmonary and gastrointestinal tissues during Ascaris suum-induced type-2 inflammation</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>Bioactive dietary components may considerably influence intestinal health and resistance to enteric disease. Proanthocyanidins (PAC) are dietary polyphenols with putative health-promoting activity that have been increasingly studied for their anti-inflammatory and immunomodulatory effects. However, whether dietary PAC can regulate type-2 immune function and inflammation at mucosal surfaces remains unclear. Here, we investigated if diets supplemented with purified PAC modulated pulmonary and intestinal mucosal immune responses during infection with the helminth parasite Ascaris suum in pigs. A. suum infection induced a type 2-biased immune response in lung and intestinal tissues, characterized by pulmonary granulocytosis, increased Th2/Th1 T cell ratios in tracheal-bronchial lymph nodes, intestinal eosinophilia, and modulation of genes involved in mucosal barrier function and immunity. We observed that PAC had only minor effects on pulmonary immune responses, regardless of concurrent A. suum infection. However, RNA-sequencing of intestinal tissues revealed that PAC significantly induced transcriptional responses related to immune function, antioxidant responses, and cellular stress activity, both in uninfected and A. suum-infected animals. A. suum infection and dietary PAC both induced distinct changes in gut microbiota composition, primarily in the jejunum and colon, respectively. Notably, PAC substantially increased Limosilactobacillus reuteri abundance in the colon of both naive and A. suum-infected animals. Thus, dietary PAC may have distinct beneficial effects on intestinal health during infection with mucosal pathogens, whilst having limited activity to modulate naturally-induced type-2 pulmonary inflammation. Our results shed further light on the mechanisms underlying the health-promoting properties of PAC-rich foods, and may aid in the design of novel dietary supplements to regulate mucosal inflammatory responses in the gastrointestinal tract.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA753018&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA753018&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>753018</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2021-08-11</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2023-05-19</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA758391" alias="PRJNA758391" center_name="Texas Biomedical Research Institute" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA758391</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="Texas Biomedical Research Institute">PRJNA758391</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <TITLE>Admixture, introgression and hybridization between Ascaris lumbricoides and suum</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>Hybridization between human and animal parasites may transfer novel pathogenic traits between species, increasing virulence, host range and negatively impacting human health. Knowing when and how often these events occurs is an essential step in achieving optimal health outcomes within a One Health framework. The human, intestinal nematode Ascaris lumbricoides infects close to a billion people world-wide and is responsible for 3,206 deaths per year. A. lumbricoides is capable of interbreeding with a closely related pig parasite, A. suum. Given the prevalence of Ascaris infections, potential zoonotic transmission, and hybridization between a human and animal parasite, it is necessary to better define the genetic relationships between these species. Previous studies have concluded that reproductive isolation between A. lumbricoides and suum is maintained via allopatry and that sympatric populations may experience interbreeding. In some populations up to 7% of worms are thought to be the product of hybridization between these species based on limited genetic sampling. We sequenced 73 samples of A. lumbricoides and A. suum collected in sympatry to examine interbreeding between these species. Our goals are to (1) examine hybridization between these species and (2) identify regions permissible or resistant to introgression.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA758391&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA758391&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>758391</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2024-05-11</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2024-07-24</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA77195" alias="PRJNA77195" center_name="NCBI" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA77195</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="NCBI">PRJNA77195</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Ascaris lumbricoides</NAME>
  <TITLE>Ascaris lumbricoides overview</TITLE>
  <UMBRELLA_PROJECT>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>6252</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Ascaris lumbricoides</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </UMBRELLA_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <CHILD_PROJECT accession="PRJEB4950"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <CHILD_PROJECT accession="PRJNA230513"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <CHILD_PROJECT accession="PRJNA391703"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <CHILD_PROJECT accession="PRJNA511012"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <CHILD_PROJECT accession="PRJNA511996"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <CHILD_PROJECT accession="PRJNA515325"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <CHILD_PROJECT accession="PRJNA556423"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA77195&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA77195&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>77195</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>ORGANISM</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2013-06-26</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA789231" alias="PRJNA789231" center_name="Jianbin Wang Lab, Biochemistry &amp; Cellular and Molecular Biology, The University of Tennessee, Knoxville" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA789231</PRIMARY_ID>
    <EXTERNAL_ID namespace="GEO">GSE189061</EXTERNAL_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="Jianbin Wang Lab, Biochemistry &amp; Cellular and Molecular Biology, The University of Tennessee, Knoxville">PRJNA789231</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Small RNA pathways in the nematode Ascaris in the absence of piRNAs</NAME>
  <TITLE>Small RNA pathways in the nematode Ascaris in the absence of piRNAs</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>Small RNA pathways play diverse regulatory roles in the nematode C. elegans. However, our understanding of small RNA pathways, their conservation, and their roles in other nematodes is limited. Here, we analyzed small RNA pathways in the parasitic nematode Ascaris. Ascaris has ten Argonautes with five worm-specific Argonautes (WAGOs) that are associated with secondary 5’-triphosphate small RNAs (22-24G-RNAs). These Ascaris WAGOs and their small RNAs target repetitive sequences (WAGO-1, WAGO-2, WAGO-3, and NRDE-3) or mature mRNAs (CSR-1, NRDE-3, and WAGO-3) and are similar to the C. elegans mutator, nuclear, and CSR-1 small RNA pathways. Ascaris CSR-1 likely functions to “license” gene expression in the absence of an Ascaris piRNA pathway. Ascaris ALG-4 and its associated 26G-RNAs target and appear to repress specific mRNAs during meiosis in the testes. Notably, Ascaris WAGOs (WAGO-3 and NRDE-3) small RNAs change their targets between repetitive sequences and mRNAs during spermatogenesis or in early embryos illustrating target plasticity of these WAGOs. We provide a unique and comprehensive view of mRNA and small RNA expression throughout nematode spermatogenesis that illustrates the dynamics and flexibility of small RNA pathways. Overall, our study provides key insights into the conservation and divergence of nematode small RNA pathways. Overall design: Examination of small RNAs associated with 7 Argonaut proteins in early embryo, female/male germline and different male germline regions of parasitic worm Ascaris.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>6253</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Ascaris suum</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA12863"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>PUBMED</DB>
        <ID>35149688</ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA789231&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA789231&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>789231</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2021-12-19</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA790705" alias="PRJNA790705" center_name="University of Veterinary Medicine Hannover" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA790705</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="University of Veterinary Medicine Hannover">PRJNA790705</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <TITLE>Modulation of the porcine intestinal microbiota in the course of Ascaris suum infection</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>The porcine roundworm Ascaris suum impairs feed conversion and weight gain, but its effects on intestinal microbiota remain largely unexplored. Therefore, modulation of the microbiota was assessed in faecal samples and intestinal content samples from infected pigs during different time points of infection.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA790705&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA790705&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>790705</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2022-04-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2023-05-17</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA80881" alias="PRJNA80881" center_name="Beijing Genomics Institute" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA80881</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="Beijing Genomics Institute">PRJNA80881</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>Ascaris suum</NAME>
  <TITLE>Ascaris suum Genome sequencing and assembly</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>This genome provides a comprehensive resource to the scientific community and underpins the development of new and urgently needed interventions (drugs, vaccines and diagnostic tests) against ascariasis and other nematodiases.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT>
      <LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>AG264</LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>
      <LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>AG265</LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>
      <LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>AG266</LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>
      <LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>AG267</LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>
      <LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>AG268</LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>
      <LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>AG269</LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>
      <LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>AG270</LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>
      <LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>AG271</LOCUS_TAG_PREFIX>
    </SEQUENCING_PROJECT>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>6253</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Ascaris suum</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA12863"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA80881&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA80881&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>80881</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2013-05-31</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA817076" alias="PRJNA817076" center_name="University of Copenhagen" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA817076</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="University of Copenhagen">PRJNA817076</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <TITLE>Dietary seaweed (Saccharina latissima) supplementation modifies the gut microbiota and induces localized immunomodulatory effects during intestinal helminth infection in pigs</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>Seaweeds have high levels of bioactive compounds, which may have beneficial effects on the health of humans and domestic animals. Dietary supplementation with seaweed has been shown to modulate gut microbiota, enhance immune function, and reduce inflammation. Furthermore, bioactive compounds of seaweed and other plants have been proposed as novel anti-parasitic treatments in livestock, which is of increasing importance as resistance to conventional anti-parasitic drugs is widespread. Here, we tested the effect of dietary seaweed (Saccharina latissima) supplementation in pigs co-infected with Ascaris suum and Oesophagostomum dentatum on parasite burdens, gut microbiota composition, and immune responses. We found that inclusion of fermented S. latissima (Fer-SL) at 8% of the diet increased gut microbiota diversity with higher relative abundances of Firmicutes, Tenericutes, Verrucomicrobia, Spirochaetes and Elusimicrobia, and lower abundance of Prevotella copri. In the absence of helminth infection, the transcription of immune-related genes in the intestine was only moderately affected by seaweed. However, Fer-SL modulated the transcriptional response to infection in a site-specific manner in the gut, with an attenuation of infection-induced gene expression in the jejunum and an amplification of gene expression in the colon. Effects on systemic immune parameters (e.g. blood lymphocyte populations) were limited, indicating the effects of Fer-SL were mainly localized to the intestinal tissues. Despite previously documented in vitro activity against pig helminths, Fer-SL inclusion did not significantly affect parasite egg excretion or worm establishment. However, we observed a trend for reduced number of liver spots, caused by migrating A. suum larvae, and reduced hatching and development of O. dentatum eggs. Collectively, our results show that although Fer-SL inclusion did not substantially reduce parasite burdens, it had seemingly positive effects on the gut environment during enteric parasite infection, which encourages continued investigations into the use of seaweeds or related products as novel tools to improve gut health.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA817076&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA817076&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>817076</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2022-03-20</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2023-05-19</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA822897" alias="PRJNA822897" center_name="Max Delbruck Center for Molecular Medicine" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA822897</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="Max Delbruck Center for Molecular Medicine">PRJNA822897</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <TITLE>Ascaris-Pig-Microbiome</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>Intestinal nematodes live in close contact with their host s intestinal microbiota and infections are extremely widespread in humans as well as companion animals, livestock and wildlife. Many nematode species have tissue migratory life stages in the absence of severe systemic inflammation of the host.&lt;/p>&lt;p>For this project the microbiome from the host and the parasite is analyzed using a model Ascaris and pigs model.&lt;/p>&lt;p>Amplicon sequencing data 16S rRNA V4 from host infected with the parasite.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA822897&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA822897&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>822897</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2023-03-31</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2023-05-17</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA850179" alias="PRJNA850179" center_name="University of Copenhagen" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA850179</PRIMARY_ID>
    <EXTERNAL_ID namespace="GEO">GSE206334</EXTERNAL_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="University of Copenhagen">PRJNA850179</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>RNA-sequencing data of liver tissue of pigs infected with parasites and adminstered proanthocyanidins (PAC)</NAME>
  <TITLE>RNA-sequencing data of liver tissue of pigs infected with parasites and adminstered proanthocyanidins (PAC)</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>We show here the transcriptional response in the liver of pigs infected or not with Ascaris suum, fed either a control pr a PAC-enriched diet Overall design: RNA was obtained from the lungs of 11 pigs infected with A. suum and 12 uninfected pigs. Within each infection group, pigs were fed either a control diet or the control diet supplemented with 1 % PAC derived from grape seed</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>9823</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Sus scrofa</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA10718"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA850179&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA850179&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>850179</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2022-06-21</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA854963" alias="PRJNA854963" center_name="University of Copenhagen" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA854963</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="University of Copenhagen">PRJNA854963</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <TITLE>Effects of dietary supplementation with fermented rapeseed and seaweed on parasite infections and gut microbiota in outdoor pigs</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>Background: Outdoor pig production systems may lead to higher exposure to infections with helminths such as Ascaris suum. Currently, anthelmintic drug treatments are the main strategy for control of helminth infection, but this is considered unsustainable due to the risk of parasites developing anthelmintic resistance. This study investigated the potential anthelmintic effect of a 2% w/w fermented rapeseed-seaweed (FRS) dietary supplement during 11-12 weeks for growing finishers and its effects on parasitic faecal egg counts (FEC), serology, gut microbiota, and systemic inflammation. The FRS comprised 6% Saccharina lastissima, 6% Ascophyllum nodosum, and 88% rapeseed meal, based on dry matter. Two different batches were used for substudy I and substudies II-IV, respectively.&lt;/p>&lt;p>Results: Supplementation of FRS tended to lower FEC and incidence of A. suum infection. However, this effect was variable depending on the batch of FRS. Inclusion of FRS in the feed influenced gut microbiota composition, and feeding with the second batch of FRS led to increased relative abundance of a range of Bacteroidetes members, e.g. Prevotella, while the unsupplemented pigs were enriched in various taxa from the Firmicutes phylum, such as Clostridium spp. Furthermore, pigs fed FRS from the second batch showed reduced daily weight gain compared to control-fed animals.&lt;/p>&lt;p>Conclusions: Collectively, our results indicate that FRS modulated the microbiota to a composition putatively associated with improved gut health, and may have some potential as a prebiotic or novel feed additive to help reduce helminth infections.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA854963&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA854963&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>854963</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2022-07-06</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2023-05-19</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA879059" alias="PRJNA879059" center_name="Chulalongkorn university" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA879059</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="Chulalongkorn university">PRJNA879059</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <TITLE>Gut bacteriome and metabolome of Ascaris lumbricoides in patients</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>We investigated and compared the bacteriomes in the gut of Ascaris lumbricoides and fecal samples of ascariasis patients collected from school-age children and young adults at Ban Mae Salid Luang and Gre Key Village, Thailand.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA879059&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA879059&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>879059</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2023-06-23</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2023-06-23</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA882448" alias="PRJNA882448" center_name="University of Tennessee Knoxville" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA882448</PRIMARY_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="University of Tennessee Knoxville">PRJNA882448</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <TITLE>The Nematode Oscheius tipulae as A Genetic Model for Programmed DNA Elimination</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>Programmed DNA elimination (PDE) is a notable exception to the paradigm of genome integrity. In metazoan, PDE often occurs during early embryogenesis, coincident with germline to somatic cell differentiation. During PDE, portions of genomic DNA are lost, resulting in reduced somatic genomes. Recent studies have described the sequences lost and chromosome behavior in metazoan. However, a system for studying the mechanisms and consequences of PDE in metazoan is lacking. Here, we established a functional and genetic model for PDE in the free-living nematode Oscheius tipulae, a member of the Rhabditidae family, which includes Caenorhabditis elegans. O. tipulae was recently suggested to eliminate DNA. Using staged embryos, we show that O. tipulae PDE occurs during embryogenesis at the 2-16 cell stages, similar to the human/pig parasitic nematode Ascaris. We identified a conserved motif, named Sequence For Elimination (SFE), for all 12 break sites on the six chromosomes at the junction of retained and eliminated DNA. SFE mutants exhibit a 'fail-to-eliminate' phenotype only at the modified sites. END-seq revealed that breaks can occur at multiple positions within the SFE, with extensive end resection followed by telomere addition to both retained and eliminated ends. We identified through END-seq in the wild-type embryos, genome sequencing of SFE mutants, and comparative genomics of 23 wild isolates a large number of functional SFEs at the chromosome ends. We suggest these alternative SFEs provide flexibility in the sequences eliminated and a fail-safe mechanism for PDE. These studies establish O. tipulae as a new, attractive model to study the mechanisms and consequences of PDE in a metazoan.</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA882448&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA882448&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>882448</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2022-10-07</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2023-05-19</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA882848" alias="PRJNA882848" center_name="420C, Biochemistry &amp; Cellular and Molecular Biology, University of Tennessee Knoxville" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA882848</PRIMARY_ID>
    <EXTERNAL_ID namespace="GEO">GSE213885</EXTERNAL_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="420C, Biochemistry &amp; Cellular and Molecular Biology, University of Tennessee Knoxville">PRJNA882848</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>The Nematode Oscheius tipulae as A Genetic Model for Programmed DNA Elimination [RNA-seq]</NAME>
  <TITLE>The Nematode Oscheius tipulae as A Genetic Model for Programmed DNA Elimination [RNA-seq]</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>Programmed DNA elimination (PDE) is a notable exception to the paradigm of genome integrity. In metazoa, PDE often occurs during early embryogenesis, coincident with germline to somatic cell differentiation. During PDE, portions of genomic DNA are lost, resulting in reduced somatic genomes. Recent studies have described the sequences lost and chromosome behavior in metazoa. However, a system for studying the mechanisms and consequences of PDE in metazoa is lacking. Here, we established a functional and genetic model for PDE in the free-living nematode Oscheius tipulae, a member of the Rhabditidae family, which includes Caenorhabditis elegans. O. tipulae was recently suggested to eliminate DNA. Using staged embryos, we show that O. tipulae PDE occurs during embryogenesis at the 2-16 cell stages, similar to the human/pig parasitic nematode Ascaris. We identified a conserved motif, named Sequence For Elimination (SFE), for all 12 break sites on the six chromosomes at the junction of retained and eliminated DNA. SFE mutants exhibit a “fail-to-eliminate” phenotype only at the modified sites. END-seq revealed that breaks can occur at multiple positions within the SFE, with extensive end resection followed by telomere addition to both retained and eliminated ends. We identified through END-seq in the wild-type embryos, genome sequencing of SFE mutants, and comparative genomics of 23 wild isolates a large number of functional SFEs at the chromosome ends. We suggest these alternative SFEs provide flexibility in the sequences eliminated and a fail-safe mechanism for PDE. These studies establish O. tipulae as a new, attractive model to study the mechanisms and consequences of PDE in a metazoan. Overall design: RNA-seq from 20 Oscheius tipulae developmental stages including early embryogenesis with staged embryos during and after PDE, as well as samples from gastrulation, morphogenesis, staged larvae (L1 – L4), dauer, post-dauer larvae, young adults, mature adults and male adults</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>141969</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Oscheius tipulae</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA882836"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA884467"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>PUBMED</DB>
        <ID>36379215</ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA882848&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA882848&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>882848</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2022-10-07</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA882849" alias="PRJNA882849" center_name="420C, Biochemistry &amp; Cellular and Molecular Biology, University of Tennessee Knoxville" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA882849</PRIMARY_ID>
    <EXTERNAL_ID namespace="GEO">GSE213883</EXTERNAL_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="420C, Biochemistry &amp; Cellular and Molecular Biology, University of Tennessee Knoxville">PRJNA882849</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>The Nematode Oscheius tipulae as A Genetic Model for Programmed DNA Elimination [ATAC-seq]</NAME>
  <TITLE>The Nematode Oscheius tipulae as A Genetic Model for Programmed DNA Elimination [ATAC-seq]</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>Programmed DNA elimination (PDE) is a notable exception to the paradigm of genome integrity. In metazoa, PDE often occurs during early embryogenesis, coincident with germline to somatic cell differentiation. During PDE, portions of genomic DNA are lost, resulting in reduced somatic genomes. Recent studies have described the sequences lost and chromosome behavior in metazoa. However, a system for studying the mechanisms and consequences of PDE in metazoa is lacking. Here, we established a functional and genetic model for PDE in the free-living nematode Oscheius tipulae, a member of the Rhabditidae family, which includes Caenorhabditis elegans. O. tipulae was recently suggested to eliminate DNA. Using staged embryos, we show that O. tipulae PDE occurs during embryogenesis at the 2-16 cell stages, similar to the human/pig parasitic nematode Ascaris. We identified a conserved motif, named Sequence For Elimination (SFE), for all 12 break sites on the six chromosomes at the junction of retained and eliminated DNA. SFE mutants exhibit a “fail-to-eliminate” phenotype only at the modified sites. END-seq revealed that breaks can occur at multiple positions within the SFE, with extensive end resection followed by telomere addition to both retained and eliminated ends. We identified through END-seq in the wild-type embryos, genome sequencing of SFE mutants, and comparative genomics of 23 wild isolates a large number of functional SFEs at the chromosome ends. We suggest these alternative SFEs provide flexibility in the sequences eliminated and a fail-safe mechanism for PDE. These studies establish O. tipulae as a new, attractive model to study the mechanisms and consequences of PDE in a metazoan. Overall design: ATAC-seq of staged Oscheius tipulae embryos</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>141969</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Oscheius tipulae</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA882836"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA884467"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>PUBMED</DB>
        <ID>36379215</ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA882849&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA882849&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>882849</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2022-10-07</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
<PROJECT accession="PRJNA882850" alias="PRJNA882850" center_name="420C, Biochemistry &amp; Cellular and Molecular Biology, University of Tennessee Knoxville" broker_name="NCBI">
  <IDENTIFIERS>
    <PRIMARY_ID>PRJNA882850</PRIMARY_ID>
    <EXTERNAL_ID namespace="GEO">GSE213884</EXTERNAL_ID>
    <SUBMITTER_ID namespace="420C, Biochemistry &amp; Cellular and Molecular Biology, University of Tennessee Knoxville">PRJNA882850</SUBMITTER_ID>
  </IDENTIFIERS>
  <NAME>The Nematode Oscheius tipulae as A Genetic Model for Programmed DNA Elimination [END-seq]</NAME>
  <TITLE>The Nematode Oscheius tipulae as A Genetic Model for Programmed DNA Elimination [END-seq]</TITLE>
  <DESCRIPTION>Programmed DNA elimination (PDE) is a notable exception to the paradigm of genome integrity. In metazoa, PDE often occurs during early embryogenesis, coincident with germline to somatic cell differentiation. During PDE, portions of genomic DNA are lost, resulting in reduced somatic genomes. Recent studies have described the sequences lost and chromosome behavior in metazoa. However, a system for studying the mechanisms and consequences of PDE in metazoa is lacking. Here, we established a functional and genetic model for PDE in the free-living nematode Oscheius tipulae, a member of the Rhabditidae family, which includes Caenorhabditis elegans. O. tipulae was recently suggested to eliminate DNA. Using staged embryos, we show that O. tipulae PDE occurs during embryogenesis at the 2-16 cell stages, similar to the human/pig parasitic nematode Ascaris. We identified a conserved motif, named Sequence For Elimination (SFE), for all 12 break sites on the six chromosomes at the junction of retained and eliminated DNA. SFE mutants exhibit a “fail-to-eliminate” phenotype only at the modified sites. END-seq revealed that breaks can occur at multiple positions within the SFE, with extensive end resection followed by telomere addition to both retained and eliminated ends. We identified through END-seq in the wild-type embryos, genome sequencing of SFE mutants, and comparative genomics of 23 wild isolates a large number of functional SFEs at the chromosome ends. We suggest these alternative SFEs provide flexibility in the sequences eliminated and a fail-safe mechanism for PDE. These studies establish O. tipulae as a new, attractive model to study the mechanisms and consequences of PDE in a metazoan. Overall design: END-seq on Oscheius tipulae early embryos</DESCRIPTION>
  <SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
    <SEQUENCING_PROJECT/>
    <ORGANISM>
      <TAXON_ID>141969</TAXON_ID>
      <SCIENTIFIC_NAME>Oscheius tipulae</SCIENTIFIC_NAME>
    </ORGANISM>
  </SUBMISSION_PROJECT>
  <RELATED_PROJECTS>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA882836"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
    <RELATED_PROJECT>
      <PARENT_PROJECT accession="PRJNA884467"/>
    </RELATED_PROJECT>
  </RELATED_PROJECTS>
  <PROJECT_LINKS>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>PUBMED</DB>
        <ID>36379215</ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-FASTQ-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA882850&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,fastq_ftp,fastq_md5,fastq_bytes]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
    <PROJECT_LINK>
      <XREF_LINK>
        <DB>ENA-SUBMITTED-FILES</DB>
        <ID><![CDATA[https://www.ebi.ac.uk/ena/portal/api/filereport?accession=PRJNA882850&result=read_run&fields=run_accession,submitted_ftp,submitted_md5,submitted_bytes,submitted_format]]></ID>
      </XREF_LINK>
    </PROJECT_LINK>
  </PROJECT_LINKS>
  <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-REFSEQ</TAG>
      <VALUE>N</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>PROJECT-ID</TAG>
      <VALUE>882850</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>NCBI-PROJECT-TYPE</TAG>
      <VALUE>SUBMISSION</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-FIRST-PUBLIC</TAG>
      <VALUE>2022-10-07</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
    <PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
      <TAG>ENA-LAST-UPDATE</TAG>
      <VALUE>2025-03-01</VALUE>
    </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTE>
  </PROJECT_ATTRIBUTES>
</PROJECT>
</PROJECT_SET>
